他对妻子说：
"你说换尿布是什么意思？
He said to his wife, "What do you mean change the baby?
我是个球员那不是我的工作"
I'm a ball player. That's not my line of work."
她转过身来，双手叉腰
表达了她的想法
And she turned around with her hands on her hips and she communicated.
她说："听着，伙计，
She said, "Look, Buster,
你把尿布像钻石一样展开
you lay the diaper out like a diamond.
把二垒放在本垒上
You put second base on home plate.
把宝宝的屁股放在投手丘上
Put the baby's bottom on the pitcher's mound.
连接一垒和三垒，从下面滑回本垒
Hook up first and third, slide home underneath.
如果开始下雨，比赛也不会取消
And if it starts to rain, the game ain't called.
你就得重新开始"
You start all over again."
所以我要表达我的想法
So I'm going to communicate.
现在，我知道
我们不能一夜之间让事情变好，
Now, I know that we can't make things right overnight,
但我们会让它变好的
but we will make them right.
我们的命运不是注定的，
Our destiny is not our fate.
而是我们的选择
It is our choice.
你和你的祖先帮助建立了这个国家
You and your forbears help build this nation.
现在，帮助我们重建它
Now, help us rebuild it.
非常感谢你们
Thank you very much.
谢谢您，总统先生
Thank you, Mr. President.
干得好，总统先生
Good job, Mr. President.
"生牛皮"正在移动
Rawhide's on the move.
一切安全
All clear.
进行得很顺利，先生
Went great, sir.
嗯，回忆往事的一趟
Boy, a trip down memory lane.
罗伊，几十年没见到他了
他是劳工总会的
Haven't seen him in decades, Roy, with AFL-CIO.
哦，他说你们俩曾在好莱坞
与一个叫索雷尔的人斗争过
Oh, he said the two of you fought with a guy in Hollywood, named Sorrell.
索雷尔赫伯·索雷尔
Sorrell. Herb Sorrell.
是的，他为苏联人工作，
Yes, he was working for the Soviets,
试图通过工会渗透好莱坞
trying to infiltrate Hollywood through the unions.
罗伊和我以后都叫他"气坏了"
Roy and I used to call him,"sore-as-hell" after that.
日程上接下来是什么？
What's next on the agenda?
"生牛皮"正从南出口出来
Rawhide coming through the south exit.
准备直升机...
Prepare the chopper...
我母亲常说，
My mother used to say,
"生活中发生的一切都有原因，
"Everything in life happens for a reason,
即使是最令人沮丧的挫折
even the most disheartening setbacks.
到最后，一切，
And in the end, everything,
甚至看似随机的命运转折
even seemingly random twists of fate
都是神圣计划的一部分"
is all a part of the divine plan."
把他带出来！把他带出来！
Get him out! Get him out!
此刻细节非常模糊
Details are very sketchy at this moment.
我们不知道究竟发生了什么
我们不知道事情的顺序
We don't know precisely what happened. We don't know the sequence.
首先，总统是安全的
First of all, the president is safe.
这正如--
That is just as--
- 请原谅
- 鲍勃·伯科威茨
- Pardon me please. -  Bob Berkowitz.
你好，鲍勃？
Hello, Bob?
我会等待后台的人来这里告诉我们
I'll wait for somebody in the back room to come up here and tell us.
我们之前向您报告说总统没有受伤
We had been reporting to you that the president was not injured.
白宫刚刚在过去几分钟内确认
The White House has confirmed now just in the last few minutes
里根总统确实被枪击了
that President Reagan has indeed been shot.
他没有在交流
He isn't communicating.
- 拉里，我们能问你一个问题吗？
- 拉里，
-  Larry, can we ask you a question? -  Larry,
有任何证据表明刺客
是为苏联工作的吗？
is there any evidence the assassin was working for the Soviets?
- 拉里...  - 我不能说就这样
-  Larry... - I can't say. That's it.
我们已经得到确认...
We have gotten confirm...
共产党人在俄罗斯
通过武力夺取了政权
Communists have seized power by force in Russia.
任何阻碍革命的人都将被清除
Anyone standing in the way of revolution will be removed.
一道铁幕已经降临在这片大陆上
An Iron Curtain has descended across the continent.
极权主义政权的种子
在苦难和战争中滋长
The seeds of totalitarian regimes are nurtured by misery and war.
它们在贫困和冲突的
邪恶一面蔓延和发展
They spread and go on the evil side of poverty and strife.
当对更好生活的希望消失时
它们达到全面增长
They reach their full growth when the hope of a better life has died.
我们必须保持那种希望活着！
We must keep that hope alive!
世界目睹了第一颗原子弹带来的
The world witnessed a new level of destruction
新程度的毁灭
in the first atomic bomb.
这种原子力量的展示
This show of atomic force
只是未来事物的警告
is only a warning of things to come.
苏联通过暴力和恐吓
Soviet Union has by violence and intimidation
侵犯了波兰
乌克兰和捷克斯洛伐克的权利，
bordered the rights of Poland, Ukraine, and Czechoslovakia
把数百万人关在无法逃脱的监狱里
holding millions in a prison unable to escape.
今天世界的焦点集中在柏林，
The world is focused today on Berlin
那里东西方正面对峙
where East and West face off.
苏联政权试图关闭其在东德的边境，
The Soviet regime looks to close its border
阻止那些逃离
in East Germany against those fleeing
极权主义镇压的人
the totalitarian crackdown.
卡斯特罗对古巴的接管
Castro's takeover of Cuba
为苏联提供了一个基地，
secures the Soviets a base
用于针对美国的核威胁
for nuclear aggression aimed at the United States.
现在，是时候让这个国家
Now, it is time for this nation to take
在太空成就方面
发挥明确的领导作用了，
a clearly leading role in space achievement,
这在许多方面可能掌握着
我们在地球上未来的关键
which in many ways may hold the key to our future on Earth.
你还担心他们在监听吗?
Do you still worry they are listening?
他们很久以前就不再听我的了
They stopped listening to me a long time ago.
不是我我正派他来见你
Not me. I'm sending him to see you.
这已经不再是老年人的战斗了
This is no longer a fight for old men.
也许不是
但他是我们最年轻的内阁成员
Perhaps not, but he's our youngest cabinet member
正在被培养成为下一任总统
being groomed to be the next president.
他经验不多,
He has little experience,
但我们有些人相信
他可以成为下一任领导人
but some of us believe he can be the next leader.
然而,他需要
从我们的错误中学习
However, he will need to learn from our mistakes.
你是指我的错误吗?
You mean my mistakes?
啊,试着把这看作一个机会
Ah, try to look at this as an opportunity
来纠正错误
to make things right.
还有其他人知道他要来见我吗?
Does anyone else know he's coming to see me?
希望没有
Let's hope not.
- 你好 - 你好
- Hello. - Hello.
我来见维克多·彼得罗维奇
I'm here to see,Viktor Petrovich.
请进
Please come in.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你见我,同志
Thank you for seeing me, Comrade.
"同志"?
"Comrade"?
我们现在已经不怎么用这个词了
We don't use that term much any longer.
是出于尊重
Offered in respect.
对你,以及同样值得尊重的
那个时代
For you, and a time that deserves equal respect.
1981年
1981.
哦
Oh.
特别的
Special.
那么...
So...
是什么让母亲俄罗斯的
冉冉升起的新星
what brings the rising star of Mother Russia
来拜访一个——一个老间谍呢?
to visit with a-- an old spy?
向你问一个问题
To ask just one question of you.
为什么?
Why?
- "为什么"? - 如果我即将重新获得
- "Why"? - If I'm about to regain
我们在这个世界上应有的地位
我必须知道
our rightful place in this world, I must know
为什么我们30年前失败了
why we failed 30 years ago.
为什么我们甚至没有战斗就放弃了?
Why we gave up without even a fight?
为什么我们允许自己成为
曾经伟大国家的一个影子?
Why did we allow ourselves to become a mere shadow of our once great nation?
比我更聪明的人...
Wiser men than I...
已经回答过这个问题了
have already answered that.
但我不满意
Not to my satisfaction.
你凭什么认为我更有能力?
What makes you think,I am more capable?
因为你是谁,同志
Because of who you are, Comrade.
你做过什么
What you did.
而且你当时在场
And you were there.
是的,我当时在场
Yes, I was there.
我在那里
I was there.
我的正式职位是分析员
My official title was Analyst
在国家安全委员会，
at the Committee for State Security,
我们心爱的克格勃
our beloved KGB.
但我是一名心理学家
But I was a psychologist
对那些可能成为
我国威胁的人进行分析，
profiling those who could become threats to our nation,
有时甚至提前几十年
sometimes decades away.
嗯，啊
Mm, ah.
有人说，我要为
Some say,I was responsible
苏联的解体负责
for the fall of the Soviet Union.
让我们暂停这个小停滞
Let's rest this little stagnation.
是吗？什么事，同志？
Yes? What is it, Comrade?
那个演员
The actor.
他会赢
He will win.
我多年来一直在警告这个人
I've been warning about this man for many years.
准备一份档案
Prepare a file.
呃...书记同志，
Uh... Comrade Secretary,
我已经准备了几十份这样的文件
I have prepared dozens of these documents.
是的，我很感谢这一点，
Yes, and I appreciate that,
彼得罗维奇同志
Comrade Petrovich.
但去准备另一份
But go prepare another.
当然
Of course.
是的，我当时在那里
Yes, I was there.
当我开始成为分析员时
我们只有一个目标：
When I began as analyst, we had one goal:
将共产主义传播到全球每个角落
spreading communism to every corner of the globe.
有些国家我们用军事力量入侵，
Some countries we invaded with military force,
但我们对美国有特别的计划
but we had special plans for the USA.
我们试图从内部瓦解他们，
We sought to break them down from within,
战略性地渗透他们的社会
strategically infiltrating their society
甚至他们的电影业
even their movie industry.
我的任务是跟踪并
影响他们的关键人物
My assignment was to track and influence their key players
并将他们的工会合并成一个
and to merge their labor unions into one
我们可以控制的工会
which we could control.
但你问的问题是错误的
But it's the wrong question you ask.
历史从来不是关于
何时、何地、为什么、如何
History is never about when, where why, how.
它总是归结为谁
It always comes down to who.
- 准备好了吗？
- 是的，先生，我准备好了
- You ready? - Yes, sir, I'm ready.
好的罗纳德·里根，
All right. Ronald Reagan,
来给我们展示
那好莱坞式的微笑
come give us that Hollywood smile.
而我恰好被分配到
And I just so happened to have been assigned
"十字军战士"
to "The Crusader."
这是我们嘲笑他时用的称呼
That is what we mockingly called him.
它成了我的执念
It became my obsession
要理解表象之下的东西
to understand what was beneath the facade.
我学会了永远不要
将任何细节视为不重要而忽略，
And I learned to never leave a detail behind as unimportant,
因为...
because...
一切都很重要
it is all important.
结婚后，我们要生几个儿子?
After we get married, how many sons are we gonna have?
嗯，你想要几个?
Well, how many do you want?
嗯，要是能组成
一个完整的队伍就好了
Well, it would be nice to have a full team.
你最喜欢什么运动?
What's your favorite sport?
这就是问题所在
That's the trouble.
足球
Football.
卡!可以印制了!
Cut! And print it!
干得好,罗恩和简
准备拍下一个镜头
Nice work, Ron and Jane. Moving on to the next shot.
嗯,感觉挺自然的
Well, that felt pretty natural.
真的吗?哪部分?
Really? What part?
让我们聚焦那双蓝眼睛
Let's move into those baby blues.
♪ 嗯,你想荡在星星上吗? ♪
♪ Mmm, would you like to swing on a star? ♪
♪ 用罐子把月光带回家? ♪
♪ Carry moonbeams home in a jar? ♪
♪ 过得比现在更好? ♪
♪ And be better off than you are? ♪
♪ 还是你宁愿做头驴? ♪
♪ Or would you rather be a mule? ♪
但我们不仅仅是演员
But we're more than actors.
- 我们是标志,是领导者
- 没错
- We're symbols, leaders. - Yes.
我们应该谈论当今重要的问题
We should be speaking to the important issues of the day.
哦,埃迪别说了,行吗?
Oh, Eddie. Give it a rest, will you?
把那些留给编剧吧
Leave that to the writers.
你在这里还是新人,里根
You're still new here, Reagan.
相信我,电影公司控制着
我写的每一个字
Trust me, the studios control every word I write.
上帝保佑我,如果我不写,
And God help me, if I don't write,
或者你不读他们让我们说的台词
or you don't read what they tell us to.
呃,他们在付钱,道尔顿
Uh, they're paying the bills, Dalton.
- 他们应该有发言权 - 没错
- They should have some say. - Yes.
我是说,我们做得很好,不是吗?
I mean, we're doing pretty well, aren't we?
- 我觉得是的
- 你不明白,霍顿
- I think so. - You don't get it, Holden.
我们只是一个系统的传声筒,
All we are is a mouthpiece to a system,
一个社会的传声筒
一个忽视工人的社会
to a society, a society that ignores the working man.
相信我,这种情况不会持续下去
Trust me, it won't last.
那你这话是什么意思,道尔顿?
Well, what do you mean by that, Dalton?
字面意思
Exactly what it says.
亲爱的,来吧我们去跳舞
Honey, come on. Let's go dance.
等一下,亲爱的不,不,真的,
Just a second, honey. No, no, really,
给我解释一下我想知道
explain it to me. I'd like to know.
好吧,我们就说这整个美国梦的事
Well, let's just say this whole American Dream thing
并不是对每个人都一样适用
doesn't exactly apply to everyone equally.
而我们中的一些人不会坐视不管
And some of us aren't sitting still for it.
我们正在采取行动
We're doing something about it.
采取什么行动?
Doing what?
道尔顿,也许我们该改天再谈这个
Dalton, maybe we should talk about this some other time.
总有一天，你得选边站
At some point, you're gonna need to pick a side.
嗯，今晚不用
Well, not tonight.
今晚，我唯一要选的是舞伴，
Tonight, the only thing,I'm gonna pick is my dance partner
我要和我美丽的妻子跳舞
and I'm dancing with my beautiful wife.
失陪了，先生们，还有女士
If you'll excuse me, fellas, and lady.
我们一会儿回来
We'll be back.
起初他似乎并不是
我们的主要关注对象
He did not initially appear to be a great concern for us.
他忙着享受蜜月
He was too busy enjoying his honeymoon.
更不用说
还有好莱坞的光鲜亮丽
Not to mention, the Hollywood glitz and glamour.
要理解是什么让这个人与众不同，
To understand what made this man unique,
我需要了解他年少时的模样
I needed to understand the boy.
他在美国中部的一个小镇长大
He grew up in a small town in the middle of America.
他父亲给他起了个绰号
His father had a nickname for him.
他们叫他"荷兰人"
They called him "Dutch."
他很早就有在人群前讲话的经验，
He had experience speaking to crowds at an early age,
因为他的母亲内莉，
as his mother, Nelle,
鼓励他在教堂里
朗诵诗歌和圣经经文
pushed him to read poetry and Bible verses at their church.
"称为我名下的子民，
"If my people which are called by my name,
若是自卑、祷告，
shall humble themselves and pray,
寻求我的面，转离他们的恶行，
seek my face and turn from their wicked ways,
我必从天上垂听，赦免他们的罪，
then I will hear from heaven, forgive their sin,
医治他们的地"
and heal their land."
我们是上帝的子民吗？
Are we God's people?
嗯，只要选择祂，
Well, anybody can be God's people
任何人都可以成为上帝的子民
so long as they choose Him.
你是怎么这么快
就记住这些经文的？
How did you memorize those verses so fast?
我不知道 我只是读了就记住了
I don't know. I just read it and remembered.
这是天赋，荷兰人
你要寻找这些才能，
It's a gift, Dutch. You have to look for those talents
因为上帝对你的生命有计划
because God has a purpose for your life.
只有你能做的事
Something only you can do.
"不幸的是，布伦达小姐
你亲爱的丈夫谢默斯，
"Unfortunately, Miss Brenda, your dear husband, Shamus,
在健力士啤酒厂的大桶里淹死了"
drowned to death in the vat at the Guinness brewery."
"哦，我可怜的谢默斯
请告诉我他走得很快"
"Oh, me poor Shamus, please tell me he went quick."
"不，"老神父说
"No," said the old priest.
"那老家伙起来小便了三次！"
"The old bugger got up three times to pee!"
他的父亲杰克是个
有魅力的讲故事高手，
His father, Jack, was a charismatic storyteller
荷兰人把他奉为偶像
and Dutch idolized him for that.
但他看到这种才能
But he saw that talent drown
淹没在酒瓶底
in the bottom of a bottle.
杰克
Jack.
杰克，快点
Jack, come on.
快点，杰克
Come on, Jack.
你又被解雇了吗？
Did you get fired again?
他们没解雇我我自己辞职的
They didn't fire me. I quit.
- 你辞职了？
- 我有大计划在酝酿，内尔！
- You quit? - I got big things cooking, Nelle!
饶了我吧，杰克！
Spare me, Jack!
我们的房租已经拖欠了
We are already late on rent.
别逼得我们的孩子又要搬家
Do not force our children to move yet again.
唧唧歪歪的！
Blah-blah-blah-blah!
为什么杰克喝那么多威士忌？
Why does Jack drink so much whiskey?
这让他忘记
It makes him forget.
忘记什么？
Forget what?
他曾经想成为的一切
All he wanted to be.
他知道自己永远无法成为的一切
All he knows he never will be.
上帝对他的生命有计划吗？
Does God have a plan for his life?
哦，达奇，当然有
Oh, Dutch, of course He does.
不幸的是，杰克现在有其他计划
Unfortunately, Jack has other plans for now.
嘿
Hey.
打开这个
Open this.
这是我和克利弗牧师送的
It's from me and Reverend Cleaver.
他们称之为...
They call it...
廉价小说
dime-store novel
讲述一个父亲是酒鬼的男孩的故事
about a boy with a drunk for a father.
这个男孩找到了上帝
The boy finds God
然后被选入美国国会
and he is elected to the American Congress.
嗯，你必须12岁，
Well, you have to be 12,
然后经过会员资格和确认课程--
and you go through membership and confirmation class--
我知道，先生，
I know that, sir,
但必须现在就做
but it has to be now.
我读了这本书
I read the book
我想成为那个人那样
and I wanna be like that man.
罗纳德·威尔逊·里根，我为你施洗
Ronald Wilson Reagan, I baptize you
奉圣父、圣子和圣灵的名
in the name of the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit.
达奇读了这本书
Dutch reads this book.
这本书对他来说是一张路线图，
This book was a roadmap for him
描绘了善战胜恶的世界
of the world where good triumphs over evil.
这本书来，看
This book. Here, look.
俄语版
Russian copy.
但要找到我真正在寻找的东西，
But to find what I was really looking for,
我不得不回到里根当救生员的时候
I had to go back to Reagan, the lifeguard.
救命！
Help!
- 救命！ - 有人救救她！
- Help! -  Somebody save her!
- 虽然他后来声称... - 救命！
- Although he would later claim... - Help!
- ...在那些夏天里救了77条生命...
- 救救我！
- ...to have saved 77 lives... - Help me!
- ...但有一个问题是... - 救命！
- ...over those summers... - Help!
- 是否真的... - 救命！
- There was a question as to whether... - Help!
坚持住,坚持住
我来帮你了我来帮你了
Hold on, hold on. I got you. I got you.
...那些都是合法的
...those were all legitimate.
- 你还好吗? - 嗯
- You okay? - Yeah.
嗯
Yeah.
快到了
Almost there.
好了
There you go.
他还学到了履行职责
He also learned that performing his duty
并不总是会得到赞扬
would not always result in praise.
你他妈在干什么?我没事
What the hell are you doing? I was fine.
你想让我看起来像个傻瓜吗?
You trying to make me look like a fool?
对不起
I'm sorry.
三十六,三十二
Thirty-six, thirty-two.
准备!开始!
Set! Hut!
耶!
Yeah!
练得不错,先生们都过来
Good practice, gentlemen. Bring it all in.
- 在他的大学里...
- 伙计们,我有个坏消息
-  At his university... - Fellas, I got tough news.
...他正在把人们
团结在一起并解决问题
...he was bringing people together and solving problems.
- 嘿,教练! - 下周,对吧?
-  Hey, Coach! -  Next week, right?
教练
Coach.
为什么萨尔和帕尔默
不和我们一起出行?
How come Sal and Palmer aren't traveling with us?
- 他们是有色人种
- 我看得出来谢谢,教练
- They're colored. - I can see that. Thanks, Coach.
酒店不接待他们
Hotel wouldn't take 'em.
进来吧,孩子们
欢迎来到里根酒店
Come on in, boys. Welcome to Hotel Reagan.
楼上有个房间给你们,孩子们
There's a room upstairs for you, boys.
希望你们不介意和达奇一起住
I hope you don't mind sharing with Dutch.
他哥哥说他打呼噜
His brother says he snores.
那边是里根训练餐桌
That there is the Reagan training table.
谢谢您,先生
Thank you, sir.
请进
Come on in.
我就知道你会想办法的,杰克
I knew you'd come through, Jack.
现在是晚上8点,我是达奇·里根
现在播报新闻
It's 8:00 p.m., I'm Dutch Reagan. Here now the news.
新任德国总理阿道夫·希特勒宣称,
The new German Chancellor, Adolf Hitler,
他重建德国的意图是和平的,
declares that his intentions in rebuilding Germany
并将遵守所有国际协议
are peaceful and will comply with all international agreements.
- 正是通过广播... - 是啊,当然是这样
-  And it was radio... - Yeah, sure they are.
...他开始展示自己的才能
...through which he began to show his skills.
但我终于追溯到他对共产主义的蔑视
But I finally traced his disdain for communism.
那简直是人间地狱
It's hell on Earth.
人们恐惧、饥饿、分裂
People are frightened, hungry, divided.
...回溯到一个我国的异见人士
访问他的教堂时
...back to when a dissident of our country visited his church.
国家掌控和管理一切
甚至最小的细节
State runs and controls everything to the smallest detail.
你的言论,你的行为,甚至你的思想
Your speech, your actions, even your thoughts.
你知道他们首先从我们这里夺走了什么吗？
You know what they took away from us first thing?
上帝
God.
像这样的教堂
Church like this.
在苏联你找不到这样的教堂
You will not find it in the Soviet Union.
他们关闭了大部分教堂
They closed down most of them.
神职人员中，许多人要么死了
要么失踪了
And the clergy, many are dead or disappeared.
美国人应该更多地
了解共产主义者
Americans should know more about the communists
因为它正在来到这里
because it's coming here.
自由只需一代人的时间就会消亡
Freedom is only one generation away from extinction.
就这样，
And just like that,
种子被播下了
the seed was planted.
记住，
And remember,
祸从口出
loose lips sink ships.
我是罗纳德·里根
This is Ronald Reagan.
那么下次再见，
So until next time,
再见，
so long,
- 愿上帝保佑美国
- 卡
- and God bless America. -  Cut.
- 里根今天的拍摄结束了
- 对不起？
- That's a wrap on Reagan today. - Excuse me?
哦，华纳先生
大家今天的工作到此结束
Oh, Mr. Warner. That's a wrap, everyone.
老板，我惹麻烦了吗？
Am I in trouble, boss?
我们散步聊聊恭喜你
Let's have a walk. Congratulations.
嗯，演员工会副主席？我印象深刻
Vice president of Screen Actors Guild, huh? I'm impressed.
你知道你踩进了一个马蜂窝，对吧？
You know you stepped into a hornet's nest, don't you?
怎么说？
How's that?
好莱坞即将爆发另一场战争，
There's about to be another war right here in Hollywood,
一边是共产党，另一边是黑帮
with the commies on one side, the mob on the other.
而你正好夹在中间，孩子
And you're caught right in the middle, son.
好吧，杰克嘿
Okay, Jack. Hey.
让我们把话说清楚，好吗？
Let's get one thing straight, okay?
我不会为你破坏工会
I'm not gonna do any union busting for you
仅仅因为我在你的工资单上
just because,I'm on your payroll.
这对我来说是利益冲突
It's a conflict of interest for me.
这不是要瓦解工会
It's not about busting up the unions.
而是这个新团体，这个呃...
But it's this new group, this, uh...
是的，影视工会联合会
Yeah, the Conference for the Studio of Unions.
赫伯·索雷尔，他是个共产党
Herb Sorrell, he's a commie.
- 是的
- 他们不仅仅在谈罢工
- Yeah. - They're not just talking strike.
他们在谈接管所有工会
They're talking about taking over all the unions.
好吧，如果这是地盘之争
就让他们自己解决吧就这样
Well, if it's a turf war, just let them work it out. That's all.
他们不会解决的，他们会打起来，
They're not gonna work it out, they're gonna fight it out,
这就是你要发挥作用的地方
and that's where you come in.
演员是最大的工会
The actors are the biggest union.
如果他们投靠索雷尔
我现在就告诉你,
If they go to Sorrell, I'm telling you right now,
共产党就赢了
the commies win.
- 这在这里是不会发生的- 好吧,听着,
- That ain't happening here. - Well, look,
我不想卷入什么事情中间
I don't feel comfortable getting into the middle of something.
你以为你能永远当主角吗?
Do you think you're gonna be a leading man forever?
你需要面对现实,儿子
You need to face the facts, son.
这场战争夺走了你生命中最好的年华
This war took the best years of your life.
你最多还有
什么,五年时间对着镜头微笑,
You got, what, five years of smiling for the camera
直到他们把你送去退休?
until they put you out to pasture?
- 好吧,谢谢你的鼓励,杰克- 或者...
- Well, thanks for the pep talk, Jack. - Or...
你做出改变?
do you make a difference?
真正的改变
A real difference.
电影是一个平台
The movies are a platform.
我们作为演员,很自豪也很荣幸
能成为其中的一部分
That we, as actors, are proud and privileged to be a part of.
我们是美国电影的面孔和生命力
We are the face and the lifeblood of American movies.
所以我们必须保持警惕,
And so we must be vigilant
让自己意识到其他人
and make ourselves aware of others
可能会试图利用我们的平台,
that may seek to use our platform
利用我们来达到他们自己的目的
to use us for their own purposes.
♪ 在我认识的所有男孩中,我认识过不少 ♪
♪ Of all the boys I've known, and I've known some ♪
♪ 直到我第一次遇见你,我一直都很孤单 ♪
♪ Until I first met you, I was lonesome ♪
♪ 当你出现在眼前时,亲爱的,我的心变得轻盈 ♪
♪ And when you came in sight, dear, my heart grew light ♪
♪ 这个旧世界对我来说似乎变得全新 ♪
♪ And this old world seemed new to me ♪
♪ 你真的很棒,我不得不承认 ♪
♪ You're really swell, I have to admit you ♪
♪ 你值得那些真正适合你的表达 ♪
♪ Deserve expressions that really fit you ♪
♪ 所以我绞尽脑汁... ♪
* And so I've racked my brain... ♪
是我说错什么了吗?
Was it something I said?
我只是好奇
I'm just curious.
你是演员还是政客?
Are you an actor or a politician?
简,不是在这里不是现在拜托
Jane, not here. Not now. Please.
如果你在事业上投入的精力
If you put as much work into your career
能像你准备演讲那样多,
as you do making your speeches,
你现在就该拿奥斯卡了
you'd have an Oscar by now.
简...
Jane...
这是SAG这是我们的工会
This is SAG. This is our union.
成为演员工会的副主席
And being Vice President of the Screen Actors Guild
就像是上帝的恩赐我真的觉得
is like a gift from God. I really feel
我可以在这里做一些有意义的事情
like I can do something that matters here.
还有比一个有理想的演员
更糟糕的吗?
Is there anything worse than an actor with a cause?
如果你一定要毁掉你的事业
罗尼,
Kill your career if you must, Ronnie,
但请饶了我你那该死的演讲
but spare me your damn speeches.
你是个演员
You are an actor.
- 那是你的工作 - 简，别说了
- That is your job. - Jane, just don't.
- 不是政治！ - 请别说了
- Not politics! - Please don't.
- 不 - 你说"不"是什么意思？
-  No. - What do you mean "no"?
更高的工资，更好的工作条件
Higher wages, better working conditions.
这是我们都想要的
这是我们都在追求的
That's what we all want. That's what we're all going for.
而你想要关掉这一切？
And you wanna shut it all down?
你真正想要的是什么？
What is it that you really want?
一个工会，团结一致
One union, and united.
听着，你不会想与
我们开战的，里根
Look, you don't wanna go to war with us, Reagan.
但没人知道
But what nobody knew
里根是FBI的线人
was that Reagan was an FBI informant.
他的代号是T-10，
His codename T-10,
他正在揭露我们在好莱坞
日益增长的影响力
and he was exposing our growing influence in Hollywood.
华纳先生，你能提供
Mr. Warner, can you provide the name
试图渗透你公司的组织
of the leader of the organization
领导人的名字吗？
attempting to infiltrate your studio?
他的名字是索雷尔
His name is Sorrell.
赫伯·索雷尔
Herb Sorrell.
我们不会加入你，赫伯
We're not joining you, Herb.
放下没事的
Put it down. It's okay.
冷静下来冷静下来
Settle down. Settle down.
你不明白，是吗？
You don't get it, do you?
我们拥有这个城市
We own this town.
你不拥有我
You don't own me.
你不拥有他们
You don't own them.
你想现在投票吗？来吧
You wanna take a vote right now? Go ahead.
我们来投票吧！看看会发生什么
Let's put it to a vote! See what happens.
看看会发生什么
See what happens.
海登先生，依你看，
Mr. Hayden, in your opinion,
为什么共产党人的努力没有成功？
why weren't the communist's efforts successful?
只有一个问题
There was just one problem.
他们遇到了演员工会的董事会，
They ran into the Board of Directors of the Screen Actors Guild,
特别是罗纳德·里根...
in particular, Ronald Reagan...
他是对抗这件事的一人军团
who was a one-man battalion against this thing.
让我们开始工作吧
Let's go to work.
好！
Yeah!
作为一个公民，我不希望看到
As a citizen, I would not like to see
任何政党因其意识形态
any political party outlawed
而被取缔
on the basis of its ideology.
民主强大到足以抵御
Democracy is strong enough to stand up for itself
任何意识形态的侵蚀，
against the inroads of any ideology,
无论我们多么不同意它
no matter how much we may disagree with it.
因为我仍然相信,主席先生,
Because I still believe, Mr. Chairman,
民主可以处理这个问题
that democracy can handle it.
他封杀了我们
他的信息传达得很巧妙,
He had shut us down. He was clever in his message
说成为共产党员没问题,
that it was okay to be communist,
但不能同时接受我们的薪水
but not while being paid by us.
卡!大家午休时间到了
And cut! That's lunch, everybody.
- 好的干得不错
- 你也表现得很棒
-  Okay. Nice work. -  You were great too.
- 我能请你吃午饭吗?
- 当然可以我有时间
-  Can I buy you lunch? -  Sure. I have time.
- 我们去吃点东西吧
- 亲爱的...
- Let's grab a bite. - Honey...
当他妻子的事业蒸蒸日上时...
While his wife's career was skyrocketing...
- ...食堂还是我的礼服...- 妈妈!
-  ...commissary or my dress... -  Mama!
...他却被打入冷宫,
...he was reduced to the sidelines
他们的婚姻...
and their marriage...
- 也日渐恶化- 妈妈...
- deteriorated. -  Mama...
更让他心碎的是,
And to break more his damaged heart,
他们的第三个孩子克里斯汀,
their third child, Christine,
出生当天就夭折了
died the very day she was born.
我的儿子怎么样?
How's my son?
我失去了一个孩子...
I lost a child...
婚姻,事业
marriage, a career.
你觉得你儿子会怎么样?
How do you think your boy is?
你知道,内尔,
You know, Nelle,
我想我可能错过了
那整个人生目标的事
I think I kinda missed the boat on that whole purpose thing.
也许我就是另一个杰克
Maybe I'm just Jack all over again.
不,达奇
No, Dutch.
你不是你父亲
You're not your father.
要记住
Just remember
去倾听那个微小、柔和的声音,
to listen to that small, soft voice,
那个你听不到的声音
the one that you can't hear
除非你独处
unless you're alone
并保持安静,
and quiet,
全神贯注地倾听
and he has your full attention.
记住你属于谁
Remember whose you are
以及你为谁服务
and whom you serve.
有什么事吗,桑迪?
Yes, Sandy?
你能给一个女演员五分钟时间吗?
Can you give an actress five minutes?
呃...
Uh...
- 当然可以- 戴维斯小姐?
- Of course. - Miss Davis?
你好我是南希·戴维斯
Hello. I'm Nancy Davis.
你好,南希·戴维斯我是罗恩·里根
Hello, Nancy Davis. I'm Ron Reagan.
是的,我知道
Yes, I know.
- 喝杯咖啡怎么样?- 哦,好啊
- How about a cup of coffee? - Oh, sure.
- 请坐- 啊
- Have a seat. - Ah.
恐怕我一直在烦你的秘书
I'm afraid I've been a pest to your secretary.
- 哦
- 但在重要的事情上我会坚持不懈
- Oh. - But I persist when it's important.
- 加奶和糖吗?- 哦,好的,
- Cream, sugar? - Oh, well,
- 当然，呃，黑色的 - 哦！
- sure, uh, black. - Oh!
那么...我能为你做些什么
南希·戴维斯？
Well... how can I help you, Nancy Davis?
嗯，
Well,
我被列为一封支持信的签名人
I'm listed as a signer on a letter of support
这封信支持两个共产主义同情者
for two communist sympathizers
但我从未签过任何这样的信
but I never signed any such letter.
还有另一个南希·戴维斯
There's another Nancy Davis.
哦，我明白了
Oh, I see.
好吧，呃，最简单的办法就是改名字
Well, uh, the easiest thing to do, is just change your name.
在好莱坞这种事经常发生
It happens all the time in Hollywood.
哦，不不我不能那样做，不行
Oh, no. No. I cannot do that, no.
我的名字对我来说非常重要
My name is very important to me.
这是...这是我的家族
It's-it's my family.
哦，当然
Oh, of course.
呃，家族很重要
Uh, family's important.
是的
Yes.
非常重要
Very important.
那么，呃
我想只剩下一件事要做了，
So, uh, I guess there's only one thing left to do,
那就是展开一次彻底
而详细的调查
and that is to launch an exhaustive and a detailed investigation.
嗯，当然，我已经聘请了律师
Well, of course, I've retained an attorney.
哦，不需要那样
Oh, there won't be any need for that.
我们可以在晚餐时解决这个问题
We can knock this out over dinner.
- 对不起？
- 是的，呃，我们可以到时再讨论
- Excuse me? - Yes, uh, we can discuss it then.
但我不能迟到我，呃...
But I can't be late. I, uh...
是的，我明早要早早去片场
Yes, I have an early studio call tomorrow morning.
哦，好吧，我得查查我的约会簿
Oh, well, I'll have to check my date book.
我只是要...给我一下...
I'm just gonna--,Just give me...
可以吗？
Yes?
可以嗯...
Yes. Um...
好吧... 哦，我想我能安排，
Well... Oh, I think,I can manage it,
但我也要早起
but I have an early call too.
那就这么定了！
Well, then it's a date!
- 好的是的 - 好
- Yeah. Yes. - Yeah.
- 好的 - 谢谢
- Okay. - Thank you.
- 很高兴
- 再见，暂时告别
- Pleasure. - Goodbye, for now.
再见，戴维斯小姐
Bye, Miss Davis.
好的，鲍比，谢谢
Okay, Bobby, thanks.
我明早会处理那件事
I'm gonna take care of that in the morning.
- 好吧... - 看来
- Well... - Well, it looks like
我们把这地方都包场了
we've shut the place down.
哈，是的，我们做到了给你
Huh, yes, we did. Here.
哦...
Oh...
谢谢你，约瑟夫呃...
Thank you, Joseph. Uh...
- 戴维斯小姐？ - 是？
- Miss Davis? - Yes?
我明早第一件事就会处理这事
I'm gonna get on this first thing in the morning
我会亲自打所有的电话
and I'll make all the calls myself.
你的名字将从那个名单上移除
Your name will be off that list.
哦，就这么简单？
Oh, just like that?
就这么简单
Just like that.
那么，呃，
So, um,
当你不演戏或
担任演员工会主席时，
when-when you're not acting or being SAG president,
你-你喜欢怎么打发时间
里根先生？
what-what do you like to do with your time, Mr. Reagan?
嗯，我...我喜欢户外活动
Well, I... I like the outdoors.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
- 我-我打高尔夫 - 嗯
- I-I play golf. - Mm.
还有...
And...
我-我喜欢骑马
I-I love riding horses.
是的你骑马吗？
Yes. Do you ride?
- 当然，我骑嗯哼 - 你骑？
- Sure, I do. Mm-hmm. - You do?
嗯，没什么能
比得上与马的关系，对吧？
Well, there's nothing like a relationship with a horse, is there?
它们是美丽的动物
They're beautiful animals.
- 是的 - 嗯哼
- Yeah. - Mm-hmm.
哦！哦！
Ooh! Ooh!
看，就是...
Look, just...
- 我该怎么减速？ - 嗯，只要...
- How do I slow down? - Well, just...
- 哦！好的
- 你做得很好你做得很好
- Ooh! Okay. - You're doing fine. You're doing fine.
哦！哦！
Oh! Oh!
- 你骑马的样子很好看 - 哦，谢谢
- You look good on a horse. - Oh, thank you.
我有个坦白要说
I have a confession to make.
哦，是什么？
Oh, what's that?
我不会骑马
I don't ride horses.
- 真的吗？你骗过了我 - 哦！
- Really? You could have fooled me. - Oh!
嗯，这里风景很美
Well, it's beautiful up here.
过来这边
Come on over here.
- 是的，确实很美
- 感觉像是离洛杉矶有一百万英里远
- Yes, it is. - It's like we're a million miles from LA.
是的你知道
事实上我的第一次外景拍摄就在这里
Yes. You know, I did my first location shoot here in fact.
- 真的吗？ - 是的
- Really? - Yes.
我跳上那匹马的背上，
I jumped on the back of that horse,
环顾四周，然后说，"哇，我在天堂"
looked around at all this, and said, "Wow, I'm in heaven."
哦！
Oh!
是啊，这里就是天堂
Yeah, it's heaven.
你知道，我也有个坦白要说，南希
You know, I have a confession to make of my own, Nancy.
嗯
Mmm.
呃...
Uh...
我是所谓的"有瑕疵的商品"
I'm what you call,"damaged goods."
我离过婚，有孩子
I'm divorced, I got kids.
多年来没有得到一个像样的角色
I haven't had a decent role in years
而且我几乎破产了
and I'm just about broke.
这算是个好的开场白吗？
How's that for a come-on?
我们都是有瑕疵的商品，罗尼
We're all damaged goods, Ronnie.
你接下来打算做什么？我是说...
What's next for you? I mean...
你想从这个生活中得到什么？
what do you want out of this life?
我不知道，我曾经有远大的抱负
I don't know, I used to have big ambitions.
梦想
Dreams.
现在，我...
Now, I...
我不知道
我只想在这个世界上做些好事
I don't know. I just wanna do something good in this world.
产生影响
Make a difference.
我觉得你已经做到了
I think you've done that.
我也想产生影响
I'd like to make a difference too.
但我已经明白了一件事，罗尼
But I have figured something out, Ronnie.
- 什么事？ - 这真的很难
- What's that? - It's really hard
在这个生活中产生影响
to make a difference in this life
当你必须独自一人做的时候
when you have to do it alone.
嗯
Mmm.
你确定你想去吗？
Are you sure you wanna go?
你知道
这不完全是奥斯卡级别的东西
You know, this is not exactly,Academy Award stuff.
嗯，你知道我们不喜欢分开，
Well, you know we don't like to be apart,
而且我喜欢看我丈夫工作
and I love to watch my husband work.
我知道，我知道，工作就是工作
I know, I know, work's work.
再见，帕蒂！
Bye, Patti!
里根先生，您的经纪人在电话里
Mr. Reagan, your agent's on the line.
听着，卢
如果我去那里，我的职业生涯就...
Look, Lou, if I go out there, my career, it's...
完蛋了
it's dead.
卢，听我说
Lou, listen to me.
我不会去那里的
I'm not going out there.
现在是帕布斯特蓝带啤酒时间！
It is Pabst Blue Ribbon time!
- 你要喝什么？
- 我要一杯帕布斯特蓝带啤酒！
- What'll you have? - I'll have a Pabst Blue Ribbon!
- 我要一杯帕布斯特，邦佐！
- 哦，好的
- I'll take a Pabst, Bonzo! - Oh, yeah.
看来邦佐该睡觉了，各位！
Looks like it's bedtime for Bonzo, folks!
谢谢各位女士们先生们，
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen,
现在有请帕布斯特蓝带舞者！
and now the Pabst Blue,Ribbon dancers!
嗯
Mm.
女士们...
Ladies...
你们有多余的烟
do you happen to have an extra smoke
给一个小丑吗？谢谢
for a clown? Thank you.
- 谢谢 - 没问题
- Thanks. - No problem.
这个季节
我要给所有朋友送切斯特菲尔德香烟
This season, I'm sending all my friends Chesterfields.
与此同时，他作为电影明星的事业
Meanwhile, his career as movie star
继续衰落
continued to fade.
哇！我应该喝V8的！
Wow! I could've had a V8!
哦，罗尼！
Oh, Ronnie!
那是一次超级顺滑的剃须
That's a super smooth shave.
那是因为我用了吉列
That's because I used Gillette.
用樟脑酚抗菌粉舒缓你的皮肤
Soothe your skin with Campho-Phenique antiseptic powder.
在电影院或在家里
亲爱的，它们都是完美的零食
At the movies or at home, honey, they're the perfect snack.
ICEE镇上最冰冷的饮料
ICEE. The coldest drink in town
...以甜蜜低价
...at a sweet, low price.
来吧，科尔曼点燃我的火焰
Come on, Colman's. Light my fire.
他继续专注于
他作为演员工会主席的角色
He continued to focus on his role as the president of Screen Actors Guild
实际上他做得相当不错
where he did quite well, actually.
但电影机会开始消失
But the movie opportunities started to evaporate.
是的,他是一个B级电影明星
这是众所周知的
Yes, he was a B-movie star. This is well-known.
但这与失去我们的祖国有什么关系?
But what does this have to do with losing our Motherland?
共产主义不是祖国
Communism is not the Motherland.
他们才是祖国
They're the Motherland.
屠格涅夫、列夫·托尔斯泰、契诃夫
Turgenev, Leo Tolstoy, Chekhov.
那才是祖国!祖国...
That's the Motherland! The Motherland...
就在这里!
is here!
我不能我必须是...
I can't. I must be...
喂?
Hello?
哦,不
Oh, no.
罗尼?
Ronnie?
主啊,感谢你赐予我母亲
Thank you, Lord, for my mother.
请照顾她
Take care of her.
我知道你会的
I know you will.
你忠诚的仆人已经回家了
Your good and faithful servant has come home.
当他为失去母亲而哀悼时,
While he mourned the loss of his mother,
并继续为自己的事业奋斗时,
and continued to struggle with his career,
世界正在超越他
the world was passing him by.
美国和苏联
The United States and Soviet Union
现在面临新的冷战
now face off in a new Cold War.
核报复迫在眉睫
Nuclear retaliation looms.
"这些基地的目的
"The purpose of these bases
只能是为了提供对西半球的
can be none other than to provide a nuclear strike capability
核打击能力"
against the western hemisphere."
肯尼迪总统的封锁
President Kennedy's blockade
阻止了核武器进入古巴
stops the advance of nuclear weapons into Cuba.
穿越德国的移动已经停止
Movements across,Germany had stopped
因为东德人一夜之间建起了一堵墙,
as the East Germans built a wall overnight,
不仅分隔了国家,
separating not only the country,
还分隔了邻居和家人
but neighbors and family.
他成为了一家电器公司
电视节目的主持人
He became host of TV show for appliance company.
他周游全国,与工厂工人会面
He toured across the country, meeting factory workers
并发表演讲
and giving speeches.
他就像一个没有政党的政治家
He was like politician with no party.
所以,他决定将目光投向别处
So, he decided to set his sights on something else.
我们他贪婪地阅读
关于共产主义、间谍活动、
Us. He devoured books about communism, espionage,
我们对东欧的接管的书籍,
our takeover of Eastern Europe,
以及柏林墙的修建
and the construction of the Berlin Wall.
你知道我们的床要舒服得多
You know our bed's a lot more comfortable.
除非你更喜欢
惠特克·钱伯斯而不是我？
Well, unless you prefer, uh, Whittaker Chambers to me?
哦，你知道那不是真的
Oh, you know that's not true.
来床上吧，亲爱的时间不早了
Come to bed, honey. It's late.
你知道，他们只有导弹和石油
You know, all they have are missiles and oil.
如果我们让他们花掉他们没有的钱，
If we get them to spend money they don't have,
他们就无法维持自己
they can't support themselves.
- 苏联人 - 苏联人
- The Soviets. - The Soviets.
我们一直在用错误的方式
处理这个问题
We've been going about this all wrong.
我们不需要在导弹上与他们一一对应
We don't have to match them missile for missile.
我们所要做的
All we have to do
只是保持压力
is just keep up the pressure.
我们的口袋比他们深
We have deeper pockets than they do.
我还以为我嫁给了一个演员呢
And here I thought,I married an actor.
嗯，你可以随时和迪克·尼克松谈谈，
Well, you could always talk to Dick Nixon,
或者肯尼迪总统
或者你的任何政治朋友
President Kennedy, or any of your political friends.
但为什么我的丈夫似乎总能
But why is it that my husband seems to know
比他们更早知道将要发生什么呢，嗯？
what's gonna happen before they do, hmm?
- 嗯... - 是啊
- Well... - Yeah.
我曾是河边公共游泳池的救生员
I was a lifeguard at a public swimming hole on a river.
我研究那条河
And I studied that river.
我学会了如何解读水流
And I learned how to read the currents.
不仅是表面的水流
Not just the ones on the surface.
还有深藏在水下的暗流，
But also the ones that were deep underneath the water,
在水底深处流动
flowing way under.
我在这方面变得很擅长
And I got good at it.
我能在人们意识到之前
察觉到他们有麻烦了
I knew people were in trouble before they did.
穆恩，谢谢你这么快
就把你弟弟带到这里来
Moon, thank you for bringing your brother up here on such short notice.
这不容易，他不喜欢飞行
It wasn't easy, he's not a fan of flying.
好吧，我们会改善这一点的谢谢你来，里根先生
Well, we'll remedy that. Thank you for coming, Mr. Reagan.
谢谢你邀请我，塔特尔先生
Thanks for having me, Mr. Tuttle.
现在，我们听说你跨越了政治鸿沟
Now, we understand that you jumped the aisle
- 换了政党 - 嗯，
- and switched parties. - Well,
我和我哥哥都是在罗斯福时代成长的
my brother and I both, we came of age under FDR.
我们的父亲杰克是他的狂热粉丝，
Our dad, Jack, he was a huge fan,
我们也以新政民主党人的身份为荣
and we were proud to be New Deal Democrats.
那你为什么离开他们？
So why did you leave 'em?
我没有离开
I didn't.
是他们离开了我
They left me.
那么,你对为戈德华特竞选
有什么看法?
Well, how do you feel about campaigning for Goldwater?
他11月肯定会惨败
He's gonna get shellacked in November.
他不可能入主白宫
No way he takes the White House.
塔特尔先生说得对
他无法击败林登·约翰逊
Mr. Tuttle's right, he can't beat LBJ.
我很好奇,罗恩
I'm curious, Ron.
你认为我们这个时代的
主要问题是什么?
What would you say is the issue of our time?
毫无疑问
No question about it.
共产主义和苏联
Communism and the Soviet Union.
我更好奇国内问题
Domestic issues is what I'm more curious about.
还有什么比生存更关乎
国内的问题吗,塔特尔先生?
What's more domestic than survival, Mr. Tuttle?
共产主义是自由的天敌
Communism is the natural enemy of freedom.
它不会停止从外部或内部攻击我们
It won't stop attacking us from the outside or the inside.
它正在世界各地蔓延,而我们却在
And it's spreading around the world while we wring our hands
试图谈判时束手无策
trying to negotiate.
我跟你们说什么来着,伙计们?
他不只是个花瓶
What did I tell you, guys? He's not just a pretty face.
罗恩,你为什么不用行动
来证明你的观点呢?
Why don't you put your money where your mouth is, Ron?
参与进来支持戈德华特,然后参选
Get in the game. Support Goldwater and then run for office.
嗯,他肯定能以压倒性优势
当选州参议员
Well, he'd win State Senator in a landslide.
州参议员听起来怎么样?
State Senator. How does that sound?
嗯,
Well,
我曾经扮演过参议员
I played a senator once.
但我从未扮演过州长
But I've never played a governor.
在我开始关注他十七年后,
Seventeen years after,I had begun following him,
他在美国政治舞台上首次亮相
he made his debut on American political stage.
我想告诉你们
其实并不存在左派或右派
Well, I'd like to suggest to you, there is no such thing as left or right.
只有向上或向下
There's only up or down.
- 看,那是爸爸
- 我认为我们面临的问题
- Look, there's daddy. -  I believe that the issues
跨越了党派界限
confronting us cross party lines.
现在,这场竞选的一方
Now, one side of this campaign
一直在告诉我们,这次选举的问题
has been telling us that the issues of this election
是维持和平与繁荣
are the maintenance of peace and prosperity.
他们用的说辞是:
The line has been used.
"我们从未如此富足"
"We've never had it so good."
某种程度上,这是一种扭曲
Somewhere, a perversion has taken place.
难道摩西应该告诉以色列的子民
Should Moses have told the children of Israel to live
继续在法老统治下做奴隶吗?
in slavery under the pharaohs?
难道基督应该拒绝十字架吗?
Should Christ have refused the cross?
难道爱国者们应该放下枪支,
Should the patriots have thrown down their guns
拒绝发出那响彻世界的一枪吗?
and refused to fire the shot heard around the world?
你我都有勇气
You and I have the courage
对我们的敌人说...
to say to our enemies...
我们不会付出某些代价
there is a price we will not pay.
有一个界限他们不能跨越
A point beyond which they must not advance.
我们会为我们的孩子保存这个，
We'll preserve for our children this,
人类在地球上最后最好的希望，
the last best hope of man on Earth,
否则我们将判处他们迈出最后一步
or we'll sentence them to take the last step
进入千年的黑暗
into a thousand years of darkness.
当世界上伟大的力量在移动时，
When great forces are on the move in the world,
我们意识到我们是精神，而不是动物
we learn that we are spirits, not animals.
在时间和空间中，
There's something going on in time and space,
超越时间和空间，
beyond time and space,
无论我们喜欢与否，
which, whether we like it or not,
都意味着责任
spells duty.
你和我...
You and I...
与命运有一场约会
have a rendezvous with destiny.
戈德华特先生败得很惨
Mr. Goldwater lost decisively.
但十字军战士已经到来
But The Crusader had arrived.
他正在警告我们
他不怕与我们对抗
And he was putting us on notice that he was not afraid to take us on.
- 你好 - 你好
- Hello. - Hello.
哦，嗨！是你啊！
Oh, hi! It's you!
- 嗯，是的
- 你在这里做什么？
-  Well, yes. - What are doing you here?
我...我赢得了什么吗？
I-- Did I win something?
不是我们正在走访这个社区，
No. We're canvasing the neighborhood,
我正在竞选州长
我想请你投我一票
and I'm running for governor and I would like your vote.
哦，当然！当然！我...
Well, of course! Of course! I...
现在我觉得很尴尬
我忘了你的名字
Now I'm embarrassed. I forgot your name.
他的首字母能帮上忙吗？RR？
Do his initials help? RR?
亲爱的！罗伊·罗杰斯来了！
Honey! Roy Rogers is here!
而且他在竞选州长！
And he's running for governor!
他现在已经站在美国的舞台上了
He was on the US stage now.
但我的同事们仍然拒绝
认真对待他
But my colleagues still refused to take him seriously.
毕竟，他们说，
After all, they said,
"一个州长能对我们做什么呢？"
"What could state governor do to us?"
里根！里根！
Reagan! Reagan!
警察负担过重他们太多了
The police are overburdened. There's just too many of them.
这些孩子的父母在哪里？
Where are these kids' parents?
嗯，他们不全是学生
大多是煽动者
Well, they're not all students. Mostly agitators.
他们甚至不知道自己在抗议什么
They don't even know what they're protesting.
他们只是为了抗议而抗议，
They're just doing it to do it,
而且他们得到了外部帮助
and they're getting outside help.
他们提出了一系列新的要求
They've issued a new set of demands.
他们当然会这样做
Of course they have.
他们希望你亲自向他们展示
They want you to present them to them personally.
国民警卫队已经待命
The National Guard... is on standby.
他们可以在一小时内到达现场
They can be on-site within an hour.
那就是联邦介入了会有影响的
That's going federal. Ramifications for that.
社区、学校，尤其是媒体
Communities, schools, especially the press.
如果他们想谈,
If they wanna talk,
那就去谈吧
let's go talk.
爱情万岁！
Love rules!
里根州长！要爱不要战！
Governor Reagan! Make love, not war!
看他现在的样子，两样都做不到
From the looks of him, he can't do either right now.
比尔会在里面跟我们会合
Bill's gonna meet us inside.
带路吧
Lead the way.
现在要和平！现在要和平！
Peace now! Peace now!
我们想听你公开向加州人民讲话！
We want to hear you speak openly about this to the state of California!
你认为我来这里是在干什么？
Well, what do you think,I'm doing here?
如果你能出面反对警察升级行动
他们可能会听
If you would come out against the police escalation, they might listen.
你什么时候在你的学生面前站出来
When did you ever stand up in front of your students
恳求他们不要这样做？
and beg them not to do this?
他们告诉你，如果你继续进行这项建设，
They told you that they were going to destroy the university
他们就会摧毁大学
if you sought to go ahead with this construction.
- 但他们提出要谈判！ - 谈判什么？
- But they offered to negotiate! - Negotiate what?
教授，这一切发生的时候，
All of this happened, professor, the very first time
你们这些年纪大到应该懂事的人
that some of you who are old enough to know better
第一次让学生们认为他们有权选择
let students think that they have the right to choose
遵守哪些法律，
which laws they were gonna obey,
只要是以社会抗议的名义进行的
as long as it was done in the name of social protest.
我受够了
I've had enough.
我要调动国民警卫队
I'm calling in the National Guard.
嘘！
Shh!
抗议者对他施加了很大压力，
The protestors pushed him hard,
但他反击得更猛烈
but he pushed them harder.
他是个有争议的州长，
He was controversial governor,
但能做的事情有限
but limited in what he could accomplish.
至少在他最关心的事情上是这样
比如我们
At least, as far as the things he cared most about, like us.
他激怒了许多同情我们事业的人，
He enraged many sympathetic to our cause,
但他也激励了许多狂热分子，
but he also inspired many fanatics
他们会不惜一切代价
who would go to great lengths
去一睹他们英雄的风采
to get a glimpse of their hero.
罗恩，这是谁？
Ron, who's this?
年轻人，呃...
Young man, uh...
你为什么在我的院子里？
why are you in my yard?
嘿，夫人！
Hey, Mrs. Gov!
我，呃，我是达娜
I'm, uh, I'm Dana.
我是青年支持里根组织的主笔
I'm the head writer for Youth for Reagan.
他们要关闭我们
我只想和州长谈五分钟
And they're shutting us down. I just want five minutes with the Gov.
哦，天哪
Oh, for heaven's sake.
我-我会很尊重的，童子军的荣誉
I-I'll be respectful, scouts honor.
我-我不会说脏话或扔东西
I-I won't swear or throw anything.
- 我也不会烧建筑物
- 不，问题是，
- And I don't burn buildings. -  No, the problem is,
州长的日程安排得很紧
is that the governor is on a very tight schedule
他不会给你五分钟
and he won't give you five minutes.
- 他会给你一个小时- 太棒了！
- He'll give you an hour. - Sweet!
不，这一点也不棒你需要回家
No, it's not sweet. You need to go home.
请给办公室打个电话
我会确保你得到一个预约，好吗？
Please, just call the office and I'll make sure you get an appointment, okay?
- 亲爱的？一切都还好吗？
- 嘿，州长！
- Honey? Is everything all right? - Hey, Gov!
这些年轻人在我们院子里过夜
These young people spent the night in our yard.
我只想谈谈五分钟
I just wanna talk. Five minutes.
你看起来很累要来杯咖啡吗？
You look tired. How about a cup of coffee?
- 哦- 当然，伙计！
- Oh. - Hell, yeah, dude!
谢谢对不起，我是说，州长
Thank you. I'm sorry, I mean, Governor.
于是这个政客说
"我做了什么要遭受这种待遇？"
So the politician says, "What did I do to deserve this?"
圣彼得说
"嗯，我们不知道该怎么安置你，
Saint Peter said, "Well, we didn't know what to do with you,
因为你是我们这里第一个政客"
because you're the first politician we've had up here."
内尔已经离开十年了，
Nelle had been gone for a decade,
但十字军战士设法找到了其他人
but The Crusader managed to find others
他们也持有她的原教旨主义信仰
who shared her fundamentalist beliefs.
有一天晚上，我们的监视发现了
And one evening, our surveillance picked up
我听过的最奇怪的对话之一...
one of the strangest exchanges,I ever heard...
...涉及一个流行歌星，
...involving a pop star,
一个传教士，
a preacher,
和一个预言
and a prophecy.
如果你继续在我面前正直行走，
If you continue to walk uprightly before me,
你将住在宾夕法尼亚大道1600号
you will dwell at 1600 Pennsylvania Avenue.
阿门
Amen.
好吧，那真是有趣
Well, that was something.
好了，我们该走了
All right, well, we should probably head out.
- 是的，是的- 谢谢你，州长
- Yes, yes. - Thank you, Governor.
- 谢谢你，帕特- 是的，谢谢你们来
- Thank you, Pat. - Yeah, thanks for coming.
好的
Yes.
你不可能相信这个
You can't possibly believe this.
我信不信并不重要
Doesn't matter if I believe it.
他相信了吗？
Did he believe it?
谁知道呢？
Who knows?
好了，比尔，就是这里
Well, Bill, there she is.
总共688英亩
688 acres in all.
听起来差不多够了
他们要价多少？
That sounds about enough. How much they asking?
对一个诚实的政治家来说太贵了
Too much for an honest politician.
嗯，没什么比在自己的一片土地上
踩来踩去更好的了
Well, there's nothing like stomping around on your own piece of dirt.
工作和汗水，
Work and sweat,
思考你的下一步行动
think about your next move.
下一步行动
Next move.
你知道，不幸的是，他们嘲笑
You know, they taunt, unfortunately.
不会持续太久
Won't last.
苏联人，他们会一直存在
The Soviets, they're here to stay.
一个退休的州长
对苏联人无能为力
There's nothing a retired governor can do about The Soviets.
嗯，你说得对确实不多
Well, you got a point. Not much.
但是一个总统...
But a president...
他可以做一两件事
Now, he can do a thing or two.
"所以把那个乘以十亿，再翻倍，
"So multiply that by a billion, double that,
那也只是它实际深度的表面
and that's only the surface of how deep it really is.
'它'指的是我对你的爱
'It' being my love for you.
我真的比那更爱你
I really love you mucher than that.
ITWWW..."
- 在整个广阔的世界里
- In The Whole Wide World. - In The Whole Wide World.
啊
Aw.
让我想起你以前的一部电影
Reminds me of one of your old movies.
我应该有一把阳伞和一杯薄荷朱利普鸡尾酒
I should have a parasol and a mint julep.
好吧，南希宝贝
我可以划回去给你拿一个
Well, Nancy Pants, I can row back and get you one.
比尔认为我应该竞选总统
Bill thinks I should run for president.
- 哦，比尔这么认为，是吗？
- 怎么了？
- Oh, Bill thinks so, does he? - What?
- 你觉得我太老了吗？ - 不
- You think I'm too old? - No.
你看起来比实际年龄年轻20岁
You look 20 years younger than you are.
你的头脑还像钉子一样锋利
Your mind is sharp as a tack.
嗯，你知道没有你的支持
我做不到这一点
Well, you know I can't do this without your support.
你永远都会得到我的支持
You'll always have my support.
我知道我不能让你余生只是砍柴
I know I can't just let you chop wood for the rest of your life.
为什么不呢？
Why not?
实际上，我一直在思考
那个牧师在泳池边说的话
I've actually been thinking about what that preacher said by the pool.
你认为他是个怪人
You thought he was a kook.
我现在仍这么认为
I still do.
但也许他说得有道理
But maybe he was onto something.
你可能真的需要拯救我们
You just may need to save us.
晚上好今晚的对决
Good evening. Tonight's showdown
可能是我们见过的最激动人心的大会
might be the most thrilling convention we've ever seen.
现任总统和来自
他自己党内的一个强劲挑战者之间
It's a true toss-up between the incumbent president
真是难分高下
and a serious challenger from within his own party.
- 迪克认为如果他能和德鲁谈谈-- - 什么？
- Dick thinks if he can talk to Drew-- - What?
迪克认为如果他能和德鲁谈谈
宾夕法尼亚州可能会倾向我们
Dick thinks that if he can talk to Drew, Pennsylvania might go our way.
好吧我听说詹姆斯·贝克
之前已经锁定了宾夕法尼亚州
Okay. I heard James Baker had Pennsylvania on lock before.
- 他说那里还有机会
- 我们失去了俄勒冈州
- He said they're in play. - We lost Oregon.
- 俄勒冈州？ - 没戏了明白吗？
- Oregon? - It's gone. All right?
俄亥俄州、印第安纳州
佛罗里达州，或者宾夕法尼亚州，
Ohio, Indiana, Florida, or Pennsylvania,
- 它们必须向我们倾斜
- 还有人想要福特帽子吗？你呢？
- they'll have to break our way. - Anyone else looking for a Ford hat? How about you?
我觉得你需要换个帽子给你
I think you need to change that hat. Here you go.
哦，这个会很好看我把这个扔掉
Oh, that's gonna look good. I'll get rid of this.
好吧，我们可能需要重新考虑那个策略
Okay, we may need to rethink that strategy.
印第安纳州、佛罗里达州、宾夕法尼亚州
Indiana, Florida, Pennsylvania.
我会让施威克和德鲁联系
谈谈宾夕法尼亚州的事
I'll get Schweiker to connect with Drew about Pennsylvania.
- 我会回头处理俄亥俄州
- 好的我负责佛罗里达州，
- I'll circle back to Ohio. - Okay. I will take Florida,
迈克，你去和里奇还有玛丽琳谈谈...
and, Mike, why don't you go talk with Rich and Marilynn...
- 玛丽琳好的
- ...关于印第安纳州的事？行吗？
- Marilynn. Okay. - ...about Indiana? Okay?
嘿，嘿我们得为吉珀赢一场
Hey, hey. We gotta win one for the Gipper.
- 嗯？ - 加油！
- Huh? - Come on!
- 一、二、三！为了吉珀！
- 准备，开始...什么？
- One, two, three! For the Gipper! - Ready, go... What?
为了下一任美国总统，
For the next,President of the United States,
加利福尼亚州全部167票
投给罗纳德·里根州长！
California casts all 167 for Governor Ronald Reagan!
谢谢你，加利福尼亚
Thank you, California.
宾夕法尼亚联邦
The Commonwealth of Pennsylvania
投出93票支持杰拉尔德·福特！
has 93 votes for Gerald Ford!
西弗吉尼亚州自豪地宣布
The state of West Virginia proudly presents its vote
我们党总统候选人的投票...
on behalf of our party's candidate for the presidency...
20票投给杰拉尔德·R·福特
Twenty votes for Gerald R. Ford.
没有比政治失败
There is no defeat more bitter
更痛苦的失败了，
than a political defeat,
尤其是当你认为这是你最后的机会时
especially if you think it is your last chance.
而现在，我预测
And right now, I predict
美国人民那天晚上会说，
that the American people are going to say that night,
"杰瑞，你做得很好！
"Gerry, you've done a good job!
继续保持下去！"
Keep right on doing it!"
福特偷走了胜利，先生
Ford stole it, sir.
他像给婴儿发糖果一样
He was handing out ambassadorship
随意分发大使职位
和搭乘空军一号的机会
and rides on Air Force One like candy to babies.
幕后政治
Backstage politics.
我真正想要的，迈克，是成为那个
What I really wanted, Mike, was to be the guy
最终对苏联说"不"的人
who finally got to say "nyet" to the Soviets.
看来这不是上帝的旨意
Guess it wasn't God's will.
民主党人和共和党人
Democrats and Republicans
30年来对我们形成了统一战线
presented a united front against us for 30 years.
但我们感觉到吉米·卡特当选带来了机会
But we sensed an opportunity with the election of Jimmy Carter.
然后，在1979年，
Then, in 1979,
我最担心的事情开始成形
my worst fears began to take shape.
这是一场信心危机
It is a crisis of confidence.
是的，吉米，这确实是一场信心危机
Yes, Jimmy, it's a crisis of confidence, all right.
你在听这个吗？
Are you listening to this?
我们可以看到这场危机正在消退...
We can see this crisis drawing down...
我们是世界上最伟大的国家
我们只是忘记了这一点
We are the greatest country in the world and we have just forgotten it.
好像我没预见到这一点似的
Like I didn't see this coming.
可以说出来，罗尼
It's okay to say it, Ronnie.
好吧我会说的
Okay. I'll say it.
我想再次参选
I want to run again.
你觉得怎么样？
What do you think about that?
如果我能再来一次...
If I can do it all again...
公众的审视，对你品格的攻击，
The public scrutiny, the attacks on your character,
所有的谎言
all the lies.
但主要是，
But mainly,
我希望你能快乐
I want you to be happy.
嗯，你已经让我成为
世界上最幸福的人了
Well, you've already made me the happiest man in the world.
我一生都在与别人分享你
I've had to share you my whole life.
但...这就是我签约的内容，
But... that's what,I signed up for,
也是我爱上的人嗯
and who I fell in love with. Hmm.
对你来说还没结束，罗尼
It's not over for you, Ronnie.
你知道你必须做什么
You know what you have to do.
这一次...
And this time...
- 赢得它 - 赢得它
- Win it. - Win it.
不，总统先生，
No, Mr. President,
我们没有两位数的通货膨胀
we don't have double-digit inflation
并不是因为人民生活得太好
because the people are living too well.
我们有两位数的通货膨胀
是因为政府生活得太好了
We have double-digit inflation because the government is living too well.
我们的首要任务必须始终是世界和平
Our first priority must always be world peace.
使用武力永远是最后的手段
The use of force is always the last resort.
这些是国民医疗保险的一些要素
These are the kind of elements of a national health insurance
对美国人民来说很重要
important to the American people.
里根州长，再次表现出
他的典型作风，反对这样的提议
Governor Reagan, again, typically is against such a proposal.
你又来了
There you go again.
下周二，你们都将前往投票站做出决定
Next Tuesday, you will all go to the polls and make a decision.
当你做出那个决定时，
And when you make that decision,
我认为你最好问问自己，
I think it would be well to ask yourself,
你现在的处境比四年前好吗？
are you better off than you were four years ago?
现在在商店购物比四年前更容易吗？
Is it easier to buy things in the store than it was four years ago?
这个国家的失业率
是增加了还是减少了？
Is there more or less unemployment in the country?
美国在世界上是否仍受到尊重？
Is America as respected throughout the world?
你感到安全吗？
Do you feel as safe?
我们是否比四年前更强大？
Are we as strong as we were four years ago?
如果你的答案是"是的"，
If your answers are "yes,"
那么我想你显然知道该投票给谁
then I think it is obvious who you will vote for.
但如果你不同意...
But if you don't agree...
那么我可以建议另一个选择
then may I suggest another choice.
...并将尽我所能
...and will, to the best of my ability.
维护、保护和捍卫
Preserve, protect and defend.
美利坚合众国宪法
The Constitution of the United States.
- 愿上帝保佑你
- 愿上帝保佑我
- So help you God. - So help me God.
恭喜您，先生
Congratulations, sir.
我们将再次成为自由的典范
We will again be the exemplar of freedom
和那些尚未获得
自由的人的希望灯塔
and the beacon of hope for those who do not now have freedom.
至于自由的敌人，
As for the enemies of freedom,
他们将被提醒
they will be reminded
和平是美国人民
that peace is the highest aspiration
最崇高的愿望
of the American people.
我们将为此谈判，为此牺牲，
We will negotiate for it, sacrifice for it,
但我们绝不会为此投降
but we will not surrender for it.
现在不会，永远也不会
Now or ever.
詹姆斯·贝克在76年
为福特工作时击败了我们，
James Baker whips our butt in '76 working for Ford,
- 现在他是幕僚长了
- 这就是为什么他是幕僚长
- now he's Chief of Staff. - Well, that's why he's Chief of Staff.
埃德，一个在80%的时间里
与你意见一致的人
Ed, someone who agrees with you,80% of the time
是80%的朋友，而不是20%的敌人
is an 80% friend, not a 20% enemy.
对不起
Excuse me.
- 议长先生 - 总统先生
- Mr. Speaker. - Mr. President.
恭喜欢迎来到大联盟
Congratulations. Welcome to the Bigs.
今晚好好享受吧
因为明天我们就要开始工作了
Now you enjoy tonight because tomorrow, we go to work.
嗯，我已经对你有了充分的了解，蒂普
Well, I've been well-briefed on you, Tip.
我被告知我最好有个不错的开端
I've been told I better get a pretty good head start.
- 啊，你这很爱尔兰- 是的
- Ah, that's very Irish of you. - Yes.
你打算每天打十个回合
这就是我们这里的做事方式
You plan on going ten rounds every day, that's how we do things here.
好吧只要记住，每天都有下午6点
All right. Just remember, every day has a 6:00 p.m.
先生，您这话是什么意思？
What do you mean by that, sir?
嗯，6点之后，我们就不是政治对手了
Well, after 6:00, we're not political enemies.
我们只是两个喝啤酒的爱尔兰人
We're just two Irishmen having a beer.
成交
Deal.
女士们先生们
美国第一夫人和总统
Ladies and gentlemen, the First Lady and President
美利坚合众国总统
of the United States of America.
- 你愿意赏脸吗？- 当然
- Would you do me the honor? - Of course.
♪ 我的眼睛崇拜你 ♪
♪ My eyes adored you ♪
♪ 尽管我从未碰触过你 ♪
♪ Though I never laid a hand on you ♪
♪ 我的眼睛崇拜你 ♪
♪ My eyes adored you ♪
♪ 就像离我一百万英里远，
♪ Like a million miles away from me,
♪ 你看不到我是多么崇拜你... ♪
♪ You couldn't see how I adored you... ♪
每个人都是为你而来，
Everyone's here for you,
对新的明天感到兴奋
excited for a new tomorrow.
哦他们只是在看我和房间里
最漂亮的女孩跳舞
Oh. They're just watching me dance with the prettiest girl in the room.
嗯
Huh.
你知道，我经常想象这一刻
You know, I've thought about this moment a lot.
在76年之后...
And after '76...
嗯，我只是没想到它会发生
Well, I just didn't think it would happen.
我知道
I knew.
我一直都知道
I always knew.
♪ 直到我们成长为你我 ♪
♪ 'Til we grew into the me and you ♪
♪ 各自走上不同的道路 ♪
♪ Who went our separate ways ♪
♪ 我的眼睛崇拜你 ♪
* My eyes adored you ♪
♪ 尽管我从未碰触过你 ♪
♪ Though I never laid a hand on you ♪
♪ 我的眼睛崇拜你... ♪
♪ My eyes adored you... ♪
女士们先生们，美国总统
Ladies and gentlemen, The President of the United States.
谢谢，谢谢
Thank you, thank you.
各位，请坐下
Everybody, just be seated.
早上好，各位，早上好
Good morning, everyone, good morning.
现在父亲找不到他乐观的小儿子
Now the father can't find his little optimistic son
所以他呼唤他
小男孩从那堆巨大的粪便中冒出头来，
so he calls out to him and the little boy pops out of that huge pile of manure,
说，"是的，爸爸？"
says, "Yes, Dad?"
父亲说，"你在里面干什么？"
The father says, "What are you doing in there?"
小男孩说，"嗯，有这么多粪便，
And the little boy says, "Well, with all this manure,
我知道里面肯定有一匹小马"
I know there's gotta be a pony in there somewhere."
总之，那是我父亲最喜欢的笑话
Anyway, that was my father's favorite joke.
女士们先生们，我们自己也有一匹小马，
And, ladies and gentlemen, we have a pony ourselves,
那就是美国人民，
and it's the American people,
我们会尽我们所能
为他们做一切
and we're gonna do everything for them that we can.
我们只需要把他们挖出来嗯
We just have to dig 'em out. Mm.
他还没当上总统半个小时，
He wasn't President for one half-hour
伊朗就释放了被扣押了一年半的
before Iran released the American hostages
美国人质
they had been holding for a year and a half.
正如他的支持者所说，
It was morning in America,
这是美国的黎明
as his supporters would say.
但仅仅几天之后，
But in just a few days,
这个黎明就几乎像来时一样迅速消失了
that morning nearly disappears as quickly as it had come.
你们和你们的先辈建立了我们的国家，
You and your forbears built our nation,
现在请帮助我们重建它
now help us rebuild it.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
不，我喜欢更亮一些哦，还有黄色，
No, I like it brighter. Oh, and the yellow,
- 你知道，罗尼喜欢--
- 酒店发生了枪击事件
- you know, Ronnie loves-- - There's been a shooting at the hotel.
- 什么？ - 没事的，夫人
- What? - It's all right, ma'am.
您的丈夫没有中弹
Your husband wasn't hit.
带我去那里
Get me there.
夫人，我不能这么做
Ma'am, I can't do that.
现在就带我去，否则我自己走过去
Get me there now or I'm walking.
有点呼吸困难
A little hard to breath.
就在他的胳膊下面
Right here under his arm.
你告诉我他没有中弹
You told me he wasn't hit.
- 不，他中弹了
- 他中弹的位置在哪里？
- No, he was. - Where was he hit?
我不知道他们正在寻找子弹
I don't know. They're looking for the bullet.
- 什么？ - 吉姆·布雷迪头部中弹了
- What? - And Jim Brady was shot in the head.
里根女士，对不起
任何人都不允许进去
Miss Reagan, I'm sorry, no one's permitted back there.
- 你不会想看到他--
- 他必须知道我在这里
- You don't wanna see him-- - He has to know I'm here.
- 好吧
- 是的对不起，让一下！
- Yeah, okay. - Yes. Excuse me. Excuse me!
我们又给他输了300毫升
We've given him another 300 cc.
他已经失去了三分之一的血液
He's lost a third of his blood already.
好的准备手术
Okay. Get him prepped.
南希在哪里？
Where-- where's Nancy?
-  罗尼？ - 哦，嗨，亲爱的
-  Ronnie? - Oh, hey, honey.
- 我忘记躲开了 - 哦，亲爱的...
- I forgot to duck. - Oh, honey...
尽量不要说话
Try not to talk.
- 对不起对不起 - 你会没事的
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry. - You're gonna be okay.
- 你会没事的 - 我很好
- You're gonna be okay. - I'm fine.
里根夫人
Mrs. Reagan.
晚上好，总统先生
Good evening, Mr. President.
请告诉我你们是共和党人
Please tell me you're Republicans.
今天，总统先生，
Today, Mr. President,
我们都是共和党人
we're all Republicans.
过来...南希...
Come here... Nancy...
嗨，南希宝贝
Hi, Nancy Pants.
嗯
Mmm.
我给你带了糖果
I brought you jelly beans.
我知道你醒来后会想要的
I knew you'd want them when you woke up.
我必须相信你会醒来
I had to believe you were waking up.
没有你我可过不好
I don't do so good without you.
我应该在那里的
I should have been there.
我总是走在你的左边
I always walk on your left side.
不，不
No, no.
不
No.
但那样就会是你了
But then it would have been you.
天哪，你为了那该死的减税什么都愿意做
Boy, you'll do anything to get that damn tax cut.
我下了明确指令
100码内不允许民主党人
I left specific orders. No democrats within 100 yards.
你只能忍着了
You'll have to grin and bear it.
- 你怎么样，伙计？ - 嗯，
- How you doing, pal? - Well,
- 我不建议被枪击 - 是啊
- I don't recommend getting shot. - No.
你知道，蒂普，我想这里有...
You know, Tip, I think there is...
我想这一切都是有原因的
I think there is a reason for all this.
还有一项重大任务要完成，而且...
There's a big job left to be done, and...
无论我还剩多少时间，它...
whatever time I have left, it...
都属于祂
belongs to Him.
啊
Ah.
"即使我走过死荫的幽谷，
"Yea, though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death,
也不怕遭害，
I shall fear no evil,
- 因为你与我同在" - "...同在"
- for thou art with me." - "...with me."
"我一生一世必有恩惠慈爱
"Surely goodness and mercy will follow me all
随着我
the days of my life.
我且要住在耶和华的殿中，
And I will dwell in the house of the Lord
直到永远"
forever."
你知道，要不是你那张脸
你本可以成为一名演员
You know, you may have been an actor if it wasn't for that mug of yours.
嗯，男主角太多了
Well, there were too many leading men.
本应要了他的命，差点就成功了
It should have killed him and it almost did.
大多数人不知道当时有多危险
Most people don't know how close it came.
我们做到了吗？
Did we do it?
不，我们没有做到，
No, we didn't do it,
这并不是说类似计划的某个版本
which isn't to say that some version of a similar plan
不存在于某个抽屉里，
didn't exist in a drawer somewhere,
因为直到今天肯定还存在
as it certainly does to this day.
- 你是谁？ - 我是达娜
-  You're who? - I'm Dana.
我今天开始工作
I start work today.
就是...对，没错
It's... Yeah, right.
这是诺夫齐格的玩笑吗？
Is this Nofziger's idea of a joke?
我建议你在特勤局来之前离开
I suggest you leave before the Secret Service get here.
特勤局放我进来的
The Secret Service let me in.
我是说，你是迈克·迪弗对吧？
I mean, you're Mike Deaver, right?
一个演讲稿写手？为美国总统...
A speech writer? For the President...
...工作的？
...of the United States?
- 我想这里有点...
- 达纳，你终于来了
- I think that there's been... - Dana, you're finally here.
刚刚飞到，先生
我甚至还没找到住的地方
Just flew in, sir. I don't even have a place to stay yet.
没有在草坪上过夜，总统先生
Did not spend the night on the lawn, Mr. President.
- 所以你认识这位先生？ - 是的
- So you know this gentleman? - Yes.
我们认识很久了
We go way back.
苏联粮食报告
Soviet grain report.
睡得好吗？我们来交换一下
Nice nap. I'll trade ya.
好吧，达纳，我希望你尽快安顿下来
Well, Dana, I want you to hurry up and settle in
因为我们有很多工作要做
'cause we have a lot of work to do.
我们这里穿西装
We wear suits here.
好的，迈克是的
Right on, Mike. Yeah.
你可能有多余的西装
可以借给我在发薪日前穿吗？
Would you maybe have an extra,I could borrow before payday?
什--
Wh--
让我知道
Let me know.
第一季度的数据低于预期
First quarter numbers are below expectations.
失业率没有变化
Unemployment hasn't budged.
我认为我们应该重新审视
I think we should reexamine
一些摆在桌面上的增收措施，先生
some of the revenue enhancers on the table, sir.
增收措施？
Revenue enhancers?
增-- 这就是你们现在在华盛顿
Re-- Is that what you're calling
称呼增税的方式吗？
tax increases these days in Washington?
我向美国人民承诺
I told the American people
我会降低税收
that I would lower taxes.
所以如果这真的是你的想法，
So if that's what you really think,
那你他妈在我的政府里做什么？
then what the hell are you doing in my administration?
总统先生，我们必须平衡这个预算
Mr. President, we simply have to balance this budget.
你知道，我学到了一两件
关于经济学的事
You know, I've learned a thing or two about economics.
我在尤里卡学院主修经济学
I majored in Economics at Eureka College.
虽然不是你们的常春藤盟校，
Now, it wasn't your Ivy League college,
但我在那里学到了
伊本·赫勒敦的理论，
but there I learned about Ibn Khaldun,
他是埃及的一位统治者
he was a ruler in Egypt.
他有一个哲学观点让我很有共鸣，
And he had a philosophy that really hit home
特别是当我在好莱坞
处于94%的税率阶层时
when I was in the 94% tax bracket in Hollywood.
那就是当税率较低时，人们会有更多的钱
And that is when taxes are low, people have more money.
当人们有更多钱时，他们会买更多东西
And when people have more money, they buy more things.
这些东西必须由其他人制造，
Now, these things have to be made by other people
而他们又必须雇用更多人来帮助他们做这些事
who have to hire more people to help them do that.
至于税收，
And as for taxes,
好吧，上帝只要求10%，
well, the good Lord only asks for 10%,
为什么山姆大叔要求更多呢？
why should Uncle Sam ask for more?
总统先生，
Mr. President,
空中交通管制员威胁要罢工
the Air Traffic Controllers are threatening a strike.
- 他们可以这么做吗？ - 不行，先生
- Well, can they do that? - No, sir.
- 从法律上讲？ - 这是必要的公共服务，
- Legally? - Essential public service,
他们都签了不罢工的合同
they have all signed a no-strike contract.
合同就是合同
A contract is a contract.
我就是这么学到的
That's the way I learned it.
他们丧失了工作
They forfeited their jobs.
如果他愿意冒险
让自己的国家陷入混乱，
If he was willing to risk chaos in his own country,
我们只能想象他可能对我们做什么
we could only imagine what he might do to us.
苏联人正在公开进行全面演习
The Soviets are conducting full exercises right out in the open.
德国边境很平静，但看起来他们正在
German border is quiet but it looks like they're moving
通过铁路运送一些全新的SS-20导弹
some brand new SS-20s by rail.
已经确认了它们在柏林以东20英里处
That's confirmed. They're 20 miles east of Berlin.
每节火车车厢
都装有一枚带核弹头的弹道导弹
Each rail car contains a ballistic missile with a nuclear warhead.
约翰，他们有多少枚核导弹？
John, how many nuclear missiles do they have?
三万五千枚
Thirty-five thousand.
- 官方数字 - 那我们呢？
- Officially. - And us?
两万五千多一点，先生
Twenty-five and change, sir.
所以大约有6万枚核弹头
So roughly 60,000 nuclear warheads
互相对准
每一枚都能摧毁一座城市
pointed at each other, each one can take out a city.
差不多就是这样，总统先生
That's about the size of it, Mr. President.
所以在过去十年里，
So while we have been,
当我们一直在削减军事力量时，
over the past ten years, reducing our military,
他们一直在增加他们的武器库，
they've been building up their arsenal
并对我们嗤之以鼻，
and thumbing their noses at us,
违反我们与他们签订的每一项条约
violating every treaty that we have with them.
不仅有可能，先生，这正是正在发生的事情
More than possible, sir, that's exactly what's happening.
除了拍照记录之外，我们对此做了什么？
And what have we done about it except take a picture of it?
好吧，在你发射完前一千枚左右后，
Well, after you fire off the first thousand or so,
就没人能继续计分了，不是吗？
there's no one around to keep score, is there?
这太疯狂了
It's insane.
一个小失误,有人喝了太多伏特加,
One little mistake, somebody has too much vodka,
这一切都不重要了
none of this matters.
今天成千上万的人
聚集在梵蒂冈的圣彼得广场,
Thousands were gathered in St. Peter's Square
欢呼教皇的到来
at the Vatican today, cheering the arrival of the Pope.
但很快,枪声将庆祝变成了恐怖,
But soon, gunshots turn the celebration into horror,
教皇倒在了他的助手怀里
as the Pope collapsed into the arms of his aids.
他正在接受手术官方说法是
He's in surgery. The official story
他只是擦伤,但实际情况更糟
is that he was grazed but it's worse than that.
他们已经为他做了临终祷告
They gave him his last rites.
我们了解到什么?
What do we know?
约翰·保罗来自苏联控制下的波兰
John Paul is from Poland under Soviet control.
波兰人民渴望自治和民主
Polish people want self-rule and democracy.
团结工会运动正在席卷全国
Solidarity movement is taking over the nation.
教皇站在他们这边,
The Pope is with them,
基本上是在向莫斯科竖中指
因为他可以这么做
basically giving Moscow the middle finger because he can.
他回祖国访问基本上就像第二次降临
Visit to the homeland is basically the second coming.
事情很明显,这是莫斯科
通过保加利亚做的,总统先生
The writing's on the wall, this comes from Moscow via Bulgaria, Mr. President.
这绝对是克格勃的手笔
This is KGB all the way.
嗯,这说不通,比尔
Well, that doesn't make sense, Bill.
他们要么会创造一个殉道者,
They're either gonna create a martyr
要么会激起天主教会
or they're gonna unleash the Catholic Church
对他们的反抗
against themselves.
他们害怕了
They're scared.
教皇活下来了
The Pope lived.
现在,这位十字军战士和教皇
And now, The Crusader and the Pope
因为都从刺客的子弹下
幸存而建立了联系
shared a bond of having survived an assassin's bullet.
而他的新盟友恰好有10亿追随者
And his new ally just happened to have a billion followers.
离开波兰
Get out of Poland.
离开阿富汗
Get out of Afghanistan.
放弃十年来的条约
Throw away ten years of treaties
并消除所有核导弹
and eliminate all nuclear missiles.
用美国人的话说
勃列日涅夫的脑子都被震惊了
As they say in America, Brezhnev's mind was blown.
他在黄色纸上
He scribbles
给我写了一封私人便条?
a personal note to me on yellow paper?
给美国总统?
The President of the United States?
现在我们知道是谁射击他的了
Now we know who shot him.
他自己的国务院
His own State Department.
嗯?
Eh?
不,谢谢
No, thank you.
现在,他的新国务卿登场了,
And now, enter his new Secretary of State,
- 乔治·舒尔茨,那个老虎人 - 谁?
- George Shultz, the Tiger Man. -  The who?
他屁股上有一个老虎纹身
He had a tattoo of a tiger on his ass.
我们怎么知道的？
How do we know that?
克格勃在这里
KGB. Here.
我们就把这个小仪式结束吧
We'll just get this little ceremony over with.
这是我60年代戒烟时用的
This is what I used to quit smoking back in the '60s.
哦，我就知道
Oh, I knew it.
- 我就知道 - 什么？
- I knew it. -  What?
嗯，你可以从一个人选择
Well, you can tell a lot about a man's character
是只拿一种颜色
by if he chooses just one color
还是抓一把看出很多东西
or if he grabs a handful.
我明白了
I see.
那么，这说明我的性格如何？
And, uh, what does this say about my character?
这说明你很专注，
It says that you're focused,
你很坚定，
you're determined,
而且你不容易分心
and that you're not easily distracted.
你在这里会做得很好的
You're gonna do great here.
好吧，那么
Okay, then.
美国雇用我们做两件事
America has hired us to do two things.
让他们再次繁荣，
Let them be prosperous again,
并保证他们的安全
and keep them safe.
通过实力获得和平
Peace through strength.
我可以畅所欲言吗？
May I speak freely?
我期待你这样做
I expect it.
清晰就是力量
Clarity is power.
现在，我相信
你对这些目标很清楚
Now, I believe you are clear in these objectives.
现在，世界其他地方也需要清楚
Now, the rest of the world needs to be.
只要这些目标是你的目标
As long as those objectives are your objectives.
是的，克拉克先生这并不是说
They are, Mr. Clark. Which isn't to say
如果我看到这些目标有冲突，
that I won't push back or voice opinions
我就不会反驳或发表意见
if I see conflict in those objectives.
这正是我选择你的原因
That's exactly why I chose you.
通过实力获得和平，这有点--
Peace through strength is, it's--
这有点模糊
It's just a-a bit opaque.
我需要你阐明一个关于苏联的信息
I-I need you to articulate a message about the Soviets
让我可以传达给全世界
that I can take to the world.
嗯，那很简单
Well, that's simple.
我们赢
We win.
他们输
They lose.
你可以引用我的话
And you can quote me.
嗯，这是一个清晰的信息
Well, that's a clear message.
- 嘿，达奇，你要去哪？ - 来啊，达奇！
- Hey, Dutch, where you going? - Come on, Dutch!
- 胆小鬼！ - 四眼仔！
- Scaredy-cat! - Four eyes!
那就是一直威胁你的男孩？
That's the boy that's been threatening you?
- 每天都是 - 过来！
-  Every day. -  Get over here!
- 妈宝男
- 他明天也会在那里
- Mama's boy. - He'll be there tomorrow too.
这就是恶霸的行为
直到你勇于反抗他们
That's what bullies do until you stand up to them.
是时候解决这个问题了，达奇
It's time for you to settle this, Dutch.
去吧
Go on.
来啊，妈宝男
Come on, Mama's boy.
打他
Get him.
有点软
It's a little soft.
我们会改进的，先生
We'll get it there, sir.
达纳？我们谈谈
Dana? A word.
我看你还有一只脚留在加利福尼亚
Well, I see you still have one foot in California.
我即将发动本世纪最大的战争
I am about to start the biggest war of this century.
也许是有史以来最大的
Maybe of all time.
而我不会开一枪
And I'm not gonna fire a single shot.
我将用言语来打这场仗
I'm gonna fight it with words.
他们必须仔细权衡每一个字
And they have to count every single one of them.
所以说话要言简意赅，
So say what you mean,
言出必行
mean what you say.
我需要那个在我院子里露营的人
I need the guy who camped out in my yard.
你明白吗？
You understand?
让我们为那些生活在
And let us pray
极权主义黑暗中的人
for the salvation of those who live
祈祷救赎
in that totalitarian darkness.
让我们祈祷他们能发现
Let us pray that they will discover
认识上帝的喜悦
the joy of knowing God
让我们意识到，当他们那些未经选举的领导人
and let us be aware that while their unelected leaders
宣扬国家至上，
preach the supremacy of the State,
宣称国家凌驾于个人之上，
declare its omnipotence over individual man
并预言最终将统治
and predict its eventual domination
地球上所有的人民时，
of all the peoples of the Earth,
他们就是现代世界邪恶的焦点
they are the focus of evil in the modern world.
正如C.S.刘易斯
It was C.S. Lewis,
在他出色的《地狱来信》中所写：
who in his magnificent,Screwtape Letters wrote,
"最大的邪恶并非产生于
"The greatest evil is not done
狄更斯笔下
那些肮脏的犯罪窝点，
in those sordid dens of crime that Dickens loved to paint
也不是在集中营和劳改营中产生
nor is it done in the concentration camps and labor camps.
在那里，我们只看到了它的最终结果
In them, we see its final result.
但它的构想和指令
But it is conceived and ordered
来自于干净、铺着地毯
温暖、灯火通明的办公室，
in clear, carpeted, warmed, and well-lighted offices
来自于那些衣冠楚楚
指甲修剪整齐的安静男人，
by quiet men with white collars and cut fingernails
他们不需要提高嗓门，
who do not need to raise their voices,
而是用温和的语调
谈论兄弟情谊和和平"
but speak in soothing tones of brotherhood and peace."
要警惕忽视历史事实的诱惑，
Beware the temptation to ignore the facts of history,
以及邪恶帝国的侵略冲动
and the aggressive impulses of an evil empire.
没错！
Yes!
我认为总统的话有点不负责任
I think the President's words were a little irresponsible.
我们现在最不需要的
就是让冷战升温
Last thing we need to do is heat this Cold War up.
虽然总统今晚显然认为...
While the President clearly thought tonight...
这些人怎么回事？
What is wrong with these people?
我是说，他们到底站在谁那边？
I mean, whose side are they on, anyway?
哦，亲爱的，你不能太在意那些
Oh, honey, you can't pay any attention to that.
但我必须在意
大多数国民都在关注他们
But I have to. Most of the country is paying attention to them.
嗯，如果你觉得
那让他们大为光火，你就等着瞧吧
Well, if you think that got their undies in a wad, you just wait.
我们已经阻止核战争三十多年了
We have prevented nuclear war for more than three decades.
然而，最近已经很明显
我们不能仅仅依靠
Recently, however, it has become clear we cannot rely solely
进攻性报复来维持和平
on offensive retaliation to maintain peace.
我呼吁科学界，
I call upon the scientific community,
那些给我们核武器的人，
those who gave us nuclear weapons
现在将他们的伟大才能
用于人类和世界和平的事业
to turn their great talents now to the cause of mankind and world peace.
建造这个防御性的"导弹盾牌"，
To build this defensive,"missile shield,"
使这些武器失去作用和过时
rendering these weapons impotent and obsolete.
如果我们采取这些措施...
If we take these measures...
他从1940年他主演的一部电影中
得到这个想法
He got the idea from a movie he starred in, in 1940.
而且随着经济的繁荣
他现在有钱可以花了
And with his economy booming, he now had the money to spend.
但这东西并不存在
But it didn't exist.
小细节而已
Small detail.
- 小细节？ - 让我们这么说吧
- Small detail? - Let's just say
他一如既往地乐观
he was characteristically optimistic.
所以他是在撒谎
So he was lying.
来，吃点东西
Here. Eat something.
维克托·彼得洛维奇，它根本不存在
Viktor Petrovich, it didn't exist.
这只是科幻小说
It was science fiction.
但导弹，导弹是存在的！
But the missiles, missiles did!
没关系
Doesn't matter.
十字军正在采取行动
The Crusader was making his move.
我们知道这一点
And we knew it.
然后发生了一些事
And then something happened.
比如什么？
Like what?
大韩航空，你们正在苏联领空
Korean Airlines, you are in Soviet airspace.
立即离开
Move out now.
指挥部，没有回应
Command, there is no response.
似乎是商业航班
Appears to be commercial flight.
- 击落它- 你确定吗？
-  Shoot it down. -  Are you sure?
我看到闪烁的指示灯
I see flashing indicators.
- 击落它- 收到
-  Shoot it down. -  Copy that.
一架民航客机？
A civilian airliner?
CIA间谍飞机
CIA spy plane.
他们已经被反复警告过了
They were warned repeatedly.
那是一架商业航班！
It was a commercial flight!
两百六十九人
Two hundred and sixty-nine people
都死了，阿纳托利，
are dead, Anatoly,
其中包括我们的一位国会议员！
including one of our congressman!
- 乔治...- 你越界了
-  George... - You crossed a line.
冷战对手之间的紧张局势继续升级
Tensions between the Cold War adversaries continue to escalate.
里根总统称之为野蛮行径
President Reagan called it an act of barbarism.
北约军队在整个欧洲保持警戒状态
NATO forces remain on alert across Europe.
国内外许多人都担心
Many are concerned at home and abroad
这些行动使美国和苏联
that these actions bring the United States and the Soviet Union
离直接军事冲突更近了一步
a step closer to a direct military conflict.
三周后，
And three weeks later,
我们的雷达系统检测到了
不可想象的情况
our radar systems detected the unthinkable.
引发了一系列令人恐惧的反应
Triggering a terrifying response of action.
- 这不是演习
- 我们有确认吗？
- This is not a drill. - Do we have confirmation on this?
苏联正在加热六个地点
Soviets are heating up six sites.
那意味着1800万美国人的生命
That's 18 million,American lives.
他们以为我们要发射，先生
They think we're launching, sir.
准备进入一级战备状态
Prepare for DEFCON 1.
我需要确认
I need confirmation.
总统先生，如果这是真的
我们没时间确认了
Mr. President, if this is real, we won't have time for confirmation.
我们需要一个决定
We need a decision.
他们正在中止，先生
他们正在撤退
They're aborting, sir. They're standing down.
好的，先生我会通知他们的
Okay, sir. I'll let them know.
我们差点就...
We're that close.
看来是一群鹅触发了雷达的正面反应
Looks like a flock of geese triggered a positive radar hit.
- 天啊- 啊
- Ah, Jesus. - Ah.
我简直不敢相信
I can't believe it.
冷战正处于全面进行中
The Cold War was in full swing.
十字军战士知道
他必须继续对我们施压，
The Crusader knew he had to keep the pressure on us,
但要确保不再出现错误
but making sure there were no more mistakes.
但在他恢复对我们的讨伐之前，
But before he could resume his crusade against us,
他必须面对他的选民
he would have to face his voters.
让我们这么说吧
并不是所有人都认为他是正确的选择
And let's just say, not everyone thought he was the right choice.
啊道貌岸然的人
Ah. Goody two-shoes.
蒙代尔先生的民调支持率
一直在稳步上升
Mr. Mondale's poll numbers have been steadily rising.
人们对总统的表现表示担忧，
Concerns have been raised as the President has stumbled,
他在上一场辩论中显得疲惫不堪
appearing tired in the last debate.
里根总统很可能最终成为
President Reagan could very well end up
一位只当一届的总统
a one-term president.
那么，你如何调整通货膨胀率，呃，
So how do you adjust for inflation, uh,
在6%到12%的预测区间内？
between the six and twelve percent projections?
嗯，你知道，
Well, you know,
随着四百万...新增就业岗位的增加...
that with the adding of four million...
三百万新增就业岗位
Three million new jobs
以及失业率的变化...
and the rate of unemployment being...
好了
Okay.
停下停下
Stop. Stop.
我需要休息一下
I need a break.
总统先生，我们真的觉得...
Mr. President, we really feel that...
我-我们只需要重新来过
w-we just need to do this all over again.
不我受够了，埃德
No. I've had enough, Ed.
那个，总-总统先生，我忘了
您最喜欢的电影是什么？
Say, M-Mr. President, I forgot, what's your favorite movie?
《音乐之声》
The Sound of Music.
要不您和里根夫人今晚
What do you say, you and Mrs. Reagan
一起看这部电影怎么样？
get together and watch it tonight?
放松一下，让头脑平静下来
Relax, calm your mind.
明天您就能重新振作起来
You'll be back in the saddle tomorrow.
我们也会准备就绪
And we'll be ready to go.
- 这是个好主意 - 嗯...
- That's a great idea. -  Well...
上帝关上一扇门
就会打开一扇窗，不是吗？
when God closes a door, He opens a window, doesn't He?
先生们，
Gentlemen,
与其往他脑子里塞无用的数字，
instead of cramming his head with useless numbers,
为什么不让罗尼做真正的自己呢？
why don't you let,Ronnie be Ronnie?
好吗？
Okay?
呃，还有人有...
Uh, anybody else have...
啊哈玛莎？
Aha. Martha?
是的，父亲
Yes, Father.
你告诉我
You tell me.
弗里德里希已经告诉您了，父亲
Friedrich told you, Father.
我们去采浆果了
We were berry picking.
我忘了！你们去采浆果了
I forgot! You were berry picking.
- 是的！ - 我们喜欢采浆果
-  Yes! - We love berry picking.
- 整个下午都在采？ - 嗯哼！
-  All afternoon? - Mm-hmm!
- 我们采了成千上万个
- 成千上万个？
-  We picked thousands. - Thousands?
到处都是浆果
They were all over the place.
什么种类的浆果？
What kind of berries?
- 蓝莓，先生 - 蓝莓！
-  Blueberries, sir. - Blueberries!
- 是的！ - 是的！蓝色的！
- Yes! - Yes! Blue!
现在，呃，还太早，蓝莓还没熟
It's, uh, too early for blueberries.
那些是草莓
They were strawberries.
特雷维特先生，请向里根总统提问
Mr. Trewhitt, your question to President Reagan.
总统先生
我想提出一个已经潜伏了两三周的问题，
Mr. President, I wanna raise an issue that I think has been lurking out there
并从国家安全的角度来具体讨论
for two or three weeks, and cast it specifically
从国家安全的角度来看
in national security terms.
您已经是历史上年纪最大的总统，
You already are the oldest,President in history
您的一些幕僚说您在最近与
蒙代尔先生的交锋后感到疲惫
and some of your staff say that you were tired
与蒙代尔先生最近的交锋后感到疲惫
after your most recent encounter with Mr. Mondale.
我记得肯尼迪总统在古巴导弹危机期间
I recall yet that President Kennedy had to go for days on end
不得不连续几天几乎没有睡眠
with very little sleep during the Cuban Missile Crisis.
您是否有任何疑问，在这种情况下
Is there any doubt in your mind that you would be able to function
您是否能正常工作？
in such circumstances?
完全没有问题，特雷维特先生
Not at all, Mr. Trewhitt.
我也想让您知道，
And I want you to know that, also,
我不会在这次竞选中把年龄作为一个问题
I will not make age an issue in this campaign.
我不会为了政治目的，
I will not for political purposes,
利用我对手的年轻和缺乏经验
exploit my opponent's youth and inexperience.
就凭这一句机智的话...
And with that one thrust of wit...
他扭转了局势
he turned the tide.
美国！美国！美国！美国！
USA, USA, USA, USA!
- 他会到场的 - 您找我，长官？
- He'll be there. - You wanted to see me, sir?
不，我们会想办法的
No, we'll figure it out.
是的，约翰
Yeah. Yeah, John.
嗯，这里有传言
说你是个...骑马高手
Uh, there's a rumor around here that you're a... a horse guy.
是的，我曾为波士顿警局骑马
Yup, I rode for Boston PD.
实际上，我一直在骑马为什么问这个？
I've been riding my whole life, really. Why?
我们在加州的西部白宫
遇到了一些问题
We've been having some issues at the Western White House
- 在加州 - 什么样的问题？
- out in California. - What kind of issues?
没人会骑马
Nobody can ride.
是的，"生牛肉"不会说什么
但这挺尴尬的，
Yeah, Rawhide isn't gonna say anything but it's pretty embarrassing
当我们的人想奔跑时却只能牵着马走
when one of ours has to walk his horse when he wants to run.
你是说驰骋
You mean gallop.
是的随便了
Yeah. Whatever.
但是，呃，你想在我们出行时
负责那个细节吗？
But, uh, do you wanna head up that detail when we travel?
所以我会和...总统一起骑马？
So I'd be riding horses with the... with the President?
驾！
Giddyap.
- 好的 - 很好
- Okay. - All right.
与其他总统不同，
Unlike other presidents,
这位十字军战士并不急于与我们会面
The Crusader was in no rush to meet with us.
这造成了一个问题
This created a problem.
这是最新情况
Here's the latest.
这个，
This here,
这只是...
this is only...
如果他们不断死去,我怎么跟他们交谈呢?
How can I talk to them if they keep dying on me?
罗恩,我们正在急需能源
我们必须从某处获得它,
We are starving for energy, Ron, and we've got to get it somewhere
而且我们负担不起我们一直在支付的价格
and we can't afford what we've been paying.
但是从苏联购买?
But buying it from the Soviet Union?
你知道那笔钱直接用于
制造指向你的导弹
You know that that money is going directly into a missile pointed at you.
总统先生,
Mr. President,
给我一个替代方案
give me an alternative.
沙特已同意增加石油产量,
The Saudis have agreed to increase oil production,
只要我们从他们那里购买
而不是从俄罗斯
as long as we buy it from them, not the Russians.
如果我们能说服
我们的盟友与我们站在一起
And if we can get our friends to go along with us.
你能在国内推销这个吗?
对你的得克萨斯人?
And you can sell this at home? To your Texans?
这会使油价降到每桶不到10美元
It will drop oil to under ten dollars a barrel.
哦,我肯定会因此遭受政治打击
Oh, I'll take a political hit for it, that's for sure.
得克萨斯人喜欢赚钱
是的,他们确实如此
And Texans love to make money, yes, they do.
我们都喜欢
We all do.
但他们更爱自由
But they love their freedom even more.
先是邪恶帝国,现在又是这个
First, the Evil Empire and now this.
你似乎并不想交朋友
You're certainly not looking to make friends.
不,我不想
No, I'm not.
但也许你应该
But perhaps you should.
我见过他们的新人,戈尔巴乔夫
I met their new man, Gorbachev.
他是一个非常不同类型的俄罗斯人
He is a very different kind of Russian.
我告诉他
你是一个非常非常不同类型
And I told him you were a very, very different kind
的美国人
of an American.
- 提高征兵人数好的 - 啊!
- Pushing up the draft. All right. - Ah!
- 哦,哦,哦 - 嘿,嘿安静嘘!
- Ow! Oh, oh. - Hey, hey. Quiet. Shh!
晚上好里根总统今晚在日内瓦,
Good evening. President Reagan is in Geneva tonight
准备参加与戈尔巴乔夫的峰会
ready for the Gorbachev summit.
男爵很荣幸能在这个场合
The baron is honored to have you stay at his home
- 让您入住他的家 - 谢谢
- for this occasion. - Thank you.
请转达我们的感激之情
Please let him know how much we appreciate it.
呃...[笑] 金鱼
Uh... [chuckles] The goldfish.
似乎男爵的儿子非常喜欢它
It seems that the baron's son is very attached to it.
它每天需要喂食两次
It needs to be fed twice every day.
好的,我会亲自喂它的
Well, I will, uh, do it personally.
有些事情,你知道
我还是可以自己做的
There are a few things,I can do myself, you know?
- 他们到了 - 哦
-  They've arrived. - Oh.
哦，那么...好的
Oh, then... Yes.
我们开始吧
Here we go.
哦，不把外套脱掉
Oh, no. Coat off.
外面冷得要命
It's below freezing out there.
全世界都在关注这次会面，乔治
The whole world is watching this meeting, George.
他需要展现最佳状态
那件大衣不行
He needs to look his best, and that overcoat is not working.
好吧，你们负责政策，
Well, you guys are in charge of policy,
但即使是自由世界的领导人也有老板，
but even the leader of the free world has a boss,
而她负责形象呈现
and she's in charge of presentation.
在峰会开始之前，
And before the summit had begun,
我们发现自己已经处于劣势，
we found ourselves already at a disadvantage,
因为总统看起来比总书记更好
as the President looked better than the General Secretary.
让我一开始就说明
Let me state at the outset.
你不应该有任何幻想
You should have no illusions
认为你能使我们破产
that you can bankrupt us.
十字军从容应对...
The Crusader took it all in stride...
- 我们可以在陆地上与你匹敌...
- ...听出了其中的真意
- We can match you on land... - ...hearing it for what it was.
...以及空中和太空
...and air and space.
这是党的强制性表态
Mandatory messaging from the Party.
依我看，
As I see it,
我们不是因为武装而互不信任
we don't mistrust each other because we're armed.
我们武装
We're armed
是因为我们互不信任
because we mistrust each other.
但我认为我们都同意最重要的一点
But I think that we both agree on the most important thing.
核战争永远不可能赢
A nuclear war can never be won
也绝不能打
and must never be fought.
他确实模棱两可
He's definitely ambiguous.
这很清楚
没有任何模棱两可的地方
It's perfectly clear, there's nothing ambiguous about it.
你像往常一样占了上风
You come out ahead as you usually do.
一再违反盐巴 I和II条约
Violation after violation of SALT I and II.
违反？
这不过是你们在太空军事化而已
Violation? This is nothing more than you militarizing space.
我看到他脸上始终挂着温和的微笑
I saw a gentle smile that never left his face.
他很有魅力
但他仍然是那个狂热分子
He was disarming, but still he was the zealot
称我们为邪恶帝国的人
that called us an Evil Empire.
我们不能放松警惕
And we could not let our guard down.
你知道，我过去常常演戏
You know, I used to do a little acting
大约二百年前在好莱坞
a couple hundred years ago back in Hollywood.
让我给你展示
我们过去如何处理这种情况
Let me show you how we used to handle this sort of thing.
第二次拍摄
Take two.
你好，米哈伊尔我叫罗恩
Hello, Mikhail. My name's Ron.
你想出去散散步吗？
How would you like to go for a little walk?
他们说您，总统先生，
What they say about you, Mr. President,
"他掏空你的口袋
还让你感觉良好"
"He picks your pocket and makes you feel good about it."
嗯，我以前听过
更糟的评价，糟糕多了
Well, I've had much worse said about me before, way worse.
我也是这是我们工作的风险
As have I. Hazard of our job.
我想让您知道
I want to let you know
我们追求的是同一件事，米哈伊尔
that we seek the same thing, Mikhail.
是吗，罗恩？
Do we, Ron?
我们不是因为必须才来这里的
We are not here because we need to be.
我们渴望和平，就像您一样
We desire peace, just as you do.
但您的提议并不那么简单
But your proposal is not so simple.
哦，事实上，它很简单
Oh, actually, it is very simple.
只是不容易
It's just not easy.
但我相信您和我，我们能做到
But I believe that you and I, we can do it.
事实上，我们必须做到
In fact, we must.
世界要求我们这么做
The world demands it.
毕竟，这不就是我们
为之工作的对象吗？
And after all, isn't that who we work for?
人民和上帝
The people and the man upstairs.
啊上帝
Ah. The man upstairs.
我祖母是个虔诚的基督徒，
My grandmother was a Christian woman,
每天都去教堂
go to church every day.
之后她会说，
And after, would say,
"米哈伊尔，我今天去了教堂
"Mikhail, I went to church today.
我为无神论者祈祷了
I prayed for the atheist.
我为你祈祷了"
I prayed for you."
嗯，我想您的祖母和我的母亲
Well, I think that your grandmother and my mother
本可以成为很好的朋友
could have been very good friends.
所以您就是那个老虎人
So you're the Tiger Man.
对不起？老虎人？
Excuse me? Tiger Man?
我很喜欢美国棒球
I like American baseball, very much.
哦，是吗？您最喜欢哪支队伍？
Oh, yeah? Who's your favorite team?
纽约扬基队您呢？
New York Yankees. And you?
呃，圣路易斯红雀队
Uh, St. Louis Cardinals.
世界大赛第7场
Game 7, World Series.
很抱歉，但是什么系列赛？
Very sorry, but what series?
哦，下次您来美国时
我会确保您能看场比赛
Oh, next time you're in the States, I'll make sure you get to a game.
不，不，不 让他们谈
No, no, no, no. Let them talk.
你要是进去就被解雇了
You go in there, you're fired.
老虎人
Tiger Man.
我的提议是这样的
My proposal...
就是这个
is this.
您和我，
That you and I,
在我离任之前，
by the time that I leave office,
能将我们的导弹数量减少一半
can reduce our missile counts by half.
嗯
Hmm.
我也不是一个有耐心的人
I'm not a patient man either.
我不打算在他们完全消失之前
I do not intend to leave office
离开办公室，
before they are gone,
彻底消失
completely.
哦，不
Oh, no.
亲爱的，看我做了什么
Honey, look what I've done.
哦，天哪
Oh, dear.
也许我们可以找到另一条
Maybe we can find another one.
呃，总统先生
我们还有五分钟就要直播了
Uh, Mr. President, we-we go live in five-five minutes.
哦，我-我觉得我们应该找另一条
Oh, I-I think we should find another one.
哦，不！
Oh, no!
每个孩子都认识自己的金鱼
Every kid knows his goldfish.
我要给他写张便条
I'm gonna write him a note.
我-我们现在需要走了
W-we need to go now.
我是说，全世界都在等着
I mean, the entire world is waiting.
世界可以等
The world can wait.
我要给他写张便条
I'm going to write him a note.
- 南希... - 这就是我的罗尼
-  Nancy... - That's my Ronnie.
- 我们必须等待
- 除了同意再次会面外，
- We have to wait. -  Nothing was really agreed to yet
实际上还没有达成任何协议
beyond agreeing to meet again.
但是苏联和美国正在互相交谈，
But the Soviet Union and USA were talking to one another
而不是互相对抗
instead of at one another.
里根对抗我们的盟友包括教皇、
Reagan's allies against us included the Pope,
铁娘子撒切尔、
Thatcher, the Iron Lady,
以及西德和日本的领导人
科尔和中曾根
and leaders of West Germany and Japan, Cole and Nakasone.
我们坚定地支持你
We stand firmly behind you.
当你与戈尔巴乔夫秘书谈话时，
When you speak with Secretary Gorbachev,
你就是在为自由世界的我们发声
you are speaking for us in free world.
好吧，我们明白
Well, we understand
你被共产主义者包围着，
that you are surrounded by communists,
我们感谢你站在我们这边
and we appreciate you standing with us.
要小心记住，
Be careful. Remember,
共产主义者
为了达到目的不惜说谎
communists have no problem with lying to achieve their goals.
他们在测试你
看你是否会坚定立场
They are testing you to see if you will stand firm.
别担心我在好莱坞
就和这些家伙打过交道
Don't worry. I dealt with these guys back in Hollywood.
我背上甚至还有伤疤可以证明
I even have the scars on my back to prove it.
我向你保证，
And I promise you,
我们不会输的
we're not going to lose.
其他新闻
里根总统已经抵达冰岛雷克雅未克，
In other news, President Reagan has landed in Reykjavík, Iceland
继续与苏联总理戈尔巴乔夫
就核裁军问题进行讨论
to continue discussions with Soviet Premier Gorbachev over nuclear disarmament.
全面削减百分之五十
Fifty percent across the board reduction.
所有武器组别,战术武器
中程核武器、洲际弹道导弹
All weapons groups, tactical, INF, ICBM.
作为交换
暂停你们的战略防御计划
In exchange, suspension of your Strategic,Defense Initiative.
有人称之为"星球大战"
"Star Wars," some refer to it.
反提议
Counter proposal.
我们分享所有战略防御计划技术,
We share all SDI technology,
我们共同开发,
we develop it together,
我们甚至愿意承担费用
we'll even pay for it.
我们在十年内消除所有弹道导弹,
And we eliminate all ballistic missiles
共同完成
in ten years. Together.
你们拒绝分享石油钻探技术,
You refuse to share oil-drilling technology
却提出这个建议?
and you offer this?
战略防御计划是一个完全防御性的系统
SDI is a completely defensive system.
这就是底线,总统先生
This is the line, Mr. President.
如果你离开,
If you walk away,
你将错过成为历史上
you will have missed the chance of going down in history
为核裁军铺平道路的总统的机会
as the president who paved the way for nuclear disarmament.
你将如何向你的
"自由人民"解释这一点?
How will you explain this to your "free people?"
总统先生,
Mr. President,
我正在给你提供你总统任期内最大的胜利
I'm offering you the biggest win of your presidency.
只要放弃战略防御计划
Just drop SDI.
不
Nyet.
我们走吧,乔治
Let's go, George.
你会为这一件事失去整个协议?
You would lose the whole deal over this one thing?
这是一个公平的提议
This is a fair offer.
我的提议也是
As was mine.
我不知道我还能做什么
I don't know what more,I could have done.
你本可以说yes的
You could have said yes.
在他离开谈判桌后,
After he walked away from the negotiating table,
我们处于一个非常黑暗的境地
we were in a very dark place.
我们知道一切都结束了,
We knew it was over,
除非发生一些非凡的事情
unless something extraordinary happened.
我们又截获了
两批从古巴运往尼加拉瓜的
We've intercepted two more shipments of Soviet RPGs and AK-47s
苏联火箭筒和AK-47步枪
coming out of Cuba, headed for Nicaragua.
自由战士们躲在山里
The freedom fighters are holed up in the mountains.
这是大卫对抗歌利亚,但他们在努力坚持
It's David and Goliath, but they're making a go of it.
嗯,我喜欢这些家伙
Well, I like these guys.
他们让我想起华盛顿和大陆军
They remind me of Washington and the Continental Army.
他们需要什么?
What do they need?
他们一直需要什么?
What do they always need?
绷带、枪支和钱
Band-Aids, guns, and money.
好,给他们想要的
Well, give them what they want.
总统先生,在这件事上
我们不会得到国会的支持
Mr. President, we won't have the Congress with us on this one.
除了真相,别无其他
你愿意以上帝的名义发誓吗?
And nothing but the truth, so help you God?
- 我愿意 - 请坐
- I do. - Please be seated.
美国国会已经说了不
The American Congress had said no
不给他在尼加拉瓜的朋友们钱
to giving money to his friends in Nicaragua.
而"十字军"在中东有人质
And The Crusader had hostages in the Middle East
需要解救他们
and needed to free them.
但美国的政策是
永远不与恐怖分子谈判
But it was American policy never to negotiate with terrorists.
但在某处,一个计划诞生了
But somewhere, a plan was hatched.
里根的伊朗门事件归结为这一点
Reagan's Iran-Contra situation comes down to this.
总统知道什么,他什么时候知道的?
What did the president know, and when did he know it?
如果你们这些媒体人想要更多答案,
And if you, people of the press, want any more answers,
去问里根总统吧
you ask President Reagan.
他与我们斗争了五十年
Five decades of his struggle against us
最终归结为他能否在国内丑闻中幸存
and it came down to whether he could survive a domestic scandal.
尽管有各种wildly推测和虚假报道,
In spite of the wildly speculative and false reports,
我们不与恐怖分子谈判
we do not negotiate with terrorists
我们也没有用武器
and we did not trade arms
换取人质
for hostages.
这些指控可能构成弹劾罪
These accusations are potentially impeachable offenses.
如果属实,一些观察家认为他的总统任期
And if true, some observers believe his presidency
可能岌岌可危
could be hanging in the balance.
白宫W新闻4台记者卡尔·朗报道
For W News 4 at the White House, I'm Carl Long.
罗尼,你必须做点什么
Ronnie, you have to do something.
你看到这个了吗?
Have you seen this?
是的,我看到了
Yes, I've seen it.
你有在听这些人说话吗?
Are you listening to these people?
他们只想看到你倒台
They want nothing more than to see you burn.
你知道,他们可能笑着
叫你"总统先生",但他们恨你
You know, they may smile and call you "Mr. President," but they hate you.
他们恨你说的话
恨你的信仰,恨你这个人
They hate what you say, what you believe in, who you are.
亲爱的,我就是不能接受这一点
Honey, I just can't accept that.
不,不,你从来都不能
No, no, you never could.
你是乐观主义者
你总是想看到人性中的善
You're the optimist. You're the one who wants to see the good in people.
但我的工作就是看穿他们,保护你
But it's my job to see through them and protect you.
嗯,这就是为什么我们是如此好的搭档
Well, that's why we're such a good team.
亲爱的,你了解华盛顿
你知道它是如何运作的
Honey, you know Washington. You know the way it works.
- 这只是政治,仅此而已
- 罗尼,他们在谈弹劾!
- It's politics, that's all. - Ronnie, they're talking impeachment!
- 不会被弹劾的
- 是的,他们想毁掉你!
- No impeachment. - Yes, they wanna destroy you!
他们要对你进行审判，把你赶下台！
They're putting you on trial, removing you from office!
这已经不是政治问题了
This isn't about politics anymore.
这关系到你自己
This is about you.
一切都岌岌可危再来一个头条新闻，
Everything is at stake. One more headline,
再来一个重要证人
再来一次逮捕，他们就会这么做
one more star witness, one more arrest, and they will do it.
我已经与他们合作了
I have cooperated with them.
我任命了一名特别检察官
I appointed a special prosecutor.
我已经交出了所有我有的文件
I've turned over every document I have.
你还要我怎么做？
What would you have me do?
我要你战斗，
I want you to fight
否则这一切就结束了！
or this is all over!
你可以雇人来做
You could always hire someone.
哈！
Ha!
怎么，你在找工作吗？
Why, you looking for work?
我有份工作给你，
I got a job for you
在华盛顿
back in Washington.
你是总统
你随时可以命令我回去
You're the president. You could always order me back there.
他们会弹劾我吗，比尔？
Are they gonna impeach me, Bill?
嗯，事情正朝那个方向发展，先生
Well, it's moving in that direction, sir.
总统先生，你是我的朋友
Mr. President, you're my friend.
我只能直白地跟你说
I can only speak to you straight.
肯定有一些法律被违反了，
Some laws got broken, for sure,
不管是你违反的还是别人违反的
whether you broke them or somebody else did.
所以现在你保持沉默并聘请律师
So now you're clamming up and lawyering up.
这是错误的做法
It's the wrong move.
这让每个人都感到困惑
甚至是那些爱你的人
It confuses everybody, even the ones that love you.
人们在想，也许你是...
People are thinking that maybe you're...
我失去理智了？是的
I'm losing it? Yeah.
我听说了
I've heard it.
你认为我应该怎么做，法官？
What do you think,I should do, Judge?
做你最擅长的事
What you do best.
告诉他们真相
Tell 'em the truth.
几个月前，我向美国人民宣称
A few months ago, I told the American people
我没有以武器换取人质
that I did not trade arms for hostages.
我的内心和最好的意图
仍然告诉我这是真的，
My heart and my best intentions still tell me that's true
但事实和证据告诉我并非如此
but the facts and the evidence tell me it is not.
现在，当你犯错时应该这样做
Now, what should happen when you make a mistake is this.
你承受批评
你把事情放在正确的角度，
You take your knocks, you put things in perspective,
你集中你的精力，
you pull your energies together,
你做出改变，然后继续前进
you make changes, and you go forward.
美国人
Americans.
你做错了事，你就要付出代价
You do them wrong, you'll pay for it.
但要看着他们的眼睛
承认你犯了错误，
But look them in the eye, admit you made a mistake,
他们每次都会原谅你
they forgive you every time.
他是总统
He was president.
他必须知道
He had to know.
他仍然是那个救生员
He was still the lifeguard.
他要把他的人民带回家
He was going to get his people home.
罗恩,我对你不太满意
让我们开门见山地说吧
I'm not pleased with you, Ron. Let's just get that said right up front.
嗯,我想不出我哪里惹你生气了
玛格丽特
Well, I can't imagine how I've upset you, Margaret.
我们又要讨论格林纳达的事吗?
Are we gonna go over Grenada again?
好吧,你当然不能逃避
Well, you're certainly not walking away
雷克雅未克发生的事...
from what happened at Reykjavík...
- 不 - 看来你在挑起争端
- No. - Looks like you're picking a fight.
不,但我不怕争端
No, but I'm not afraid of one.
也许这就是为什么密特朗称你为
Perhaps that is why,Mitterrand calls you
"危险的牛仔"
a "dangerous cowboy."
嗯,
Well,
至少我有
玛格丽特·撒切尔站在我这边
at least I have,Margaret Thatcher on my side.
- 他想说出来
- 他确实想,但我们永远无法说服舒尔茨
- He wants to say it. - He does, but we'll never get it past Shultz.
我是说
这是他们最不想让他谈论的事
I mean, it's the one thing they don't want him talking about.
我在德国的家人都在谈论这个
My family in Germany is talking about it.
每个人都在谈论他需要谈论这个
Everybody is talking about it. He needs to talk about it.
他要去戴维营,然后回到这里待一天,
He's going to Camp David, then he's back here for a day,
之后他要去欧洲
我们只有一次机会让他说这个
then he's going to Europe. We have one shot to have him say this.
现在或永远不可能
It's now or never.
嘿,把这个给我!我-我来拿谢谢
Hey, give me this! I-I'll take that. Thank you.
总统先生,一些轻松的读物
Mr. President, some light reading.
嘘!
Shh!
下午好
Good afternoon.
你们好,伙计们,今天是个适合飞行的好日子
Hello, fellas, good day to fly.
不过别来桶滚
No barrel rolls though.
嗯,我想那其实是第一夫人的问题
Well, I think that's a First Lady question, actually.
你为什么要这样对戈尔巴乔夫?
Why would you do this to Gorbachev?
你知道我们花了多长时间才达到这一步
You know how long it's taken us to get to this.
他们已经坐到谈判桌前了
他们准备达成协议,
They're at the table. They're ready to make a deal
而你想让他难堪?
and you wanna embarrass him?
戈尔巴乔夫是70年来
我们在那边的第一个朋友!
Gorbachev's the first friend we've had over there in 70 years!
你不能说这个
You can't say this.
我-我恳求你听我说
I'm-I'm begging you to listen to me.
你知道,当战略防御计划
被嘲笑时我支持了你
You know, I stood by you with SDI when it was ridiculed.
我支持你对付尼加拉瓜反政府武装
I supported you with the Contras.
我甚至在雷克雅未克会谈上
弄得灰头土脸
I even walked out of Reykjavík with egg on my face.
但这次太过分了
But this goes too far.
这比"邪恶帝国"还要糟糕
This is worse than Evil Empire.
你要炸毁日内瓦
你要毁掉八年的外交努力
You're gonna blow up Geneva, you blow up eight years of diplomacy.
我们会回到原点，甚至更糟！
We'll be right back where we started from, or worse!
"清晰就是力量"
"Clarity is power."
你知道，一位伟人曾对我说过这句话
You know, a very great man once said that to me.
乔治，我们来这里是为了什么...
What are we here for, George...
不就是为了赢吗？
but to win?
在我身后矗立着一堵墙
Behind me stands a wall.
它是一个庞大屏障系统的一部分，
Part of a vast system of barriers
将整个欧洲大陆一分为二
that divide the entire continent of Europe.
一道由铁丝网、混凝土、
A gash of barbed wire, concrete,
警犬和哨塔组成的伤痕，
dogs, and guard towers,
强加了极权国家的意志
imposing the will of a totalitarian state.
只要这扇大门还关着，
As long as this gate is closed
只要这道伤疤还被允许存在，
and this scar is permitted to stand,
全人类的自由就仍是个问题
there is a question of freedom for all mankind.
极权主义世界产生落后，
The totalitarian world produces backwardness
因为它对精神造成了如此大的伤害
because it does such violence to the spirit.
阻碍了人类创造
享受甚至崇拜的冲动
Thwarting the human impulse to create, to enjoy, even to worship.
在这里，在柏林
就像这座城市本身一样，
Here in Berlin, like the city itself,
爱的象征，崇拜的象征
symbols of love, symbols of worship
是无法被压制的
cannot be suppressed.
苏联可以做出一个标志，
There is one sign that the Soviets can make,
这个标志将明确且戏剧性地推进
that would unmistakably and dramatically advance
自由与和平的事业
the cause of freedom and peace.
戈尔巴乔夫总书记，
General Secretary Gorbachev,
如果你寻求和平，
if you seek peace,
如果你寻求自由化和变革，
if you seek liberalization and change,
就来到这扇门前吧
come here to this gate.
戈尔巴乔夫先生，
Mr. Gorbachev,
打开这扇门
open this gate.
他会说出那句话吗？
Is he gonna say it?
戈尔巴乔夫先生，
Mr. Gorbachev,
推倒这堵墙
tear down this wall.
喔！
Whoo!
干得好，牛仔
Well done, cowboy.
在冷战的棋局中，
In the chess game of the Cold War,
这是将军
it was checkmate.
难以想象的事情
The unimaginable is happening
正在柏林发生
right now in Berlin.
令人震惊的事态发展在一夜之间发生
Shocking developments overnight
东德宣布其公民
as East Germany announced its citizens
可以自由前往西德
can travel freely to West Germany.
没人认为可能发生的事情
What no one thought could happen
此刻正在发生
is happening right now.
几小时内，城市爆发了庆祝活动
Within hours, the city erupted in celebration
东德和西德人民
用锤子敲打分隔他们30年的墙壁
as East and West Germans took hammers to the wall
这堵墙已经将他们分隔了30年
that had separated them for 30 years.
柏林墙倒塌两年后，
Two years, after the wall fell,
苏联不复存在
the Soviet Union was no more.
我知道他就是那个人
I knew he was the one.
他就是那个会让我们垮台的人
He was the one who would bring us down.
不是用导弹或枪支，甚至不是用政治
Not with missiles or guns or even politics.
而是用更伟大的东西
Something much greater.
人们不会为权力献出生命，
People will not give their lives for power,
也不会为国家，甚至不会为意识形态
or a State, or even ideology.
人们会为彼此献出生命，
People give their lives for one another,
为自由选择生活的方式
和为上帝而献身
for the freedom to live those lives as they choose and for God.
我们剥夺了这一点
We took that away.
十字军战士...
The Crusader...
把它还给了他们
gave it back to them.
这就是你问题的答案
And that is the answer to your question.
谢谢你，维克多·彼得罗维奇
Thank you, Viktor Petrovich.
拿去吧
Take it.
谢谢
Thank you.
晚安
Good night.
总统先生，那里发生了什么？
What's going on there, Mr. President?
这对我来说意义重大
This means something to me.
我知道你在说什么，约翰，
I know what you're saying, John,
但我不会那么做的
but I'm not gonna do it.
夫人，我需要你告诉他我们不能再这样做了
Ma'am, I need you to tell him we can't do this anymore.
我不能我不能我做不到
I can't. I can't. I can't do it.
他昨天迷路了
He got lost yesterday.
我半个小时都找不到他
I couldn't find him for half an hour.
马知道骑手不知道
自己在做什么，好吗？他...
Horses know when a rider doesn't know what he's doing, okay? He's...
他会再次被摔下来的
He's gonna get thrown again.
我不能告诉他不能再骑马了
I can't tell him that he can't ride anymore.
他太喜欢骑马了
He loves it too much.
拜托
Please.
好吧
Okay.
他更爱你，夫人
He loves you more, ma'am.
总统先生？
Mr. President?
怎么了，约翰？
What is it, John?
你知道，呃...
You know, uh...
我觉得我们骑马的乐趣
已经不如从前了
I don't think we're having as much fun riding as we used to.
哦，负责里根夫人的特工，她...
Oh, the agent on, uh...
- 负责里根夫人的特工，她...
- 你想说什么，约翰？
- On Mrs. Reagan, she is... - What do you want, John?
总统先生，我认为...
Mr. President, I don't--
我认为我们不应该再骑马了
I don't think we should ride anymore.
哦
Oh.
再骑一次
One more ride.
好的，总统先生
Yes, sir, Mr. President.
嗯
Mm.
亲爱的美国同胞们
My fellow Americans.
我最近被告知
我是数百万美国人中的一员，
I have recently been told that I am one of the millions of Americans
将会患上阿尔茨海默症
who will be afflicted with Alzheimer's disease.
此刻，我感觉很好
At the moment, I feel just fine.
我打算在上帝赐予我的余生里，
I intend to live the remainder of the years God gives me
继续做我一直在做的事情
doing the things,I have always done.
不幸的是
随着阿尔茨海默症的进展，
Unfortunately, as Alzheimer's disease progresses,
家人常常要承担沉重的负担
the family often bears a heavy burden.
我只希望有某种方法能让南希
I only wish there was some way,I could spare Nancy
免受这种痛苦的经历
from this painful experience.
我将继续与我深爱的南希
I will continue to share life's journey
和我的家人一起分享人生旅程
with my beloved Nancy and my family.
我计划享受大自然，
I plan to enjoy the great outdoors
并与我的朋友和支持者保持联系
and stay in touch with my friends and supporters.
当那一刻来临时，
When the time comes,
我相信在你们的帮助下，
I am confident that with your help,
她会以信念和勇气面对
she will face it with faith and courage.
最后，让我感谢你们，美国人民，
In closing, let me thank you, the American people,
给予我莫大的荣幸
for giving me the great honor
让我能够担任你们的总统
of allowing me to serve as your president.
当上帝召唤我回家时，无论何时，
When the Lord calls me home, whenever that may be,
我将带着对这个国家最深沉的爱
I will leave with the greatest love for this country of ours
和对其未来永恒的乐观离去
and eternal optimism for its future.
我现在开始了一段
将引领我走向人生黄昏的旅程
I now begin the journey that will lead me into the sunset of my life.
我知道对美国来说，
I know that for America,
前方永远会有光明的新黎明
there will always be a bright new dawn ahead.
谢谢你们，我的朋友们
Thank you, my friends.
愿上帝永远保佑你们
May God always bless you.
诚挚地，
Sincerely,
罗纳德·里根
Ronald Reagan.